<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 13:11:35 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 and Beyond</title>
      <link>/2020-and-beyond/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 13:11:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020-and-beyond/</guid>
      <description>Dear 2020
I&#39;m looking forward to u with
  warm heart
  pleasant smile
  empty expectations.
  opening myself
Let&#39;s bring it on!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Here is why I am losing interests on my country and I dont need help</title>
      <link>/2017-04-22-here-is-why-i-am-losing-interests-in-my-country-and-i-dont-need-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017-04-22-here-is-why-i-am-losing-interests-in-my-country-and-i-dont-need-help/</guid>
      <description>I am an Indian. A 24 year old. Spent all my 24 years so far in India except few vacations. Right through my school days, I was taught Patriotism via books, Prayers, Sports routines and early celebrations of historically important days. During those days, I felt it. The pride, the energy and the importance. But as I grew up and became an adult and especially after the arrival of the social media, I am slowly feeling the reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A 24 year old&#39;s struggle to learn Music</title>
      <link>/2017-04-22-a-24yr-olds-struggle-to-learn-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017-04-22-a-24yr-olds-struggle-to-learn-music/</guid>
      <description>Firstly listen to the below wonderful piece composed by Ludovico Einaudi
{% include video id=&amp;quot;X1DRDcGlSsE&amp;rdquo; provider=&amp;quot;youtube&amp;rdquo; %}
Did you notice the talent? The involvement? The fingers moving effortlessly with absolute passion for the tune? The background orchestra supporting like pillars of a beautiful monument? The violins and cellos. This is a thing of a beauty. Now this is one beautiful example of a sincere and a passionate work. Isn&#39;t it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop The Goddamn Car !</title>
      <link>/2015-06-17-stop-the-goddamn-car/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 05:35:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015-06-17-stop-the-goddamn-car/</guid>
      <description>Ever felt really bad after a stupid argument? over a stupid topic? with your close ones? Ever felt so exhausted after such bad moments and started to regret things? I also have encountered such moments. I recently got an important advice from my dad which was more like a solution to such kind of problems. So I thought I could share it with the world.
I admired these words so much and tried to understand it better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inspiration from within !</title>
      <link>/2015-04-20-inspiration-from-within/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 06:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015-04-20-inspiration-from-within/</guid>
      <description>In my opinion, clearly no person other than Steve Jobs will be remembered by the world for what he did to technology and design. No other batsman other than Sachin Tendulkar is rightly portrayed to be the &amp;lsquo;God of Cricket&amp;rsquo; for what he did to the game and for Indian cricket. No one other than Narayana Murthy will be appreciated in India as much for being a role model and perfect entrepreneur in the Indian IT industry.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>