<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-04-23T16:35:13+05:30</updated><id>https://themoralpanda.github.io//</id><title type="html">The Moral Panda</title><subtitle>Personal site of Vigneshwar Venkatachalapathi. Software Engineer, Blogger, Problem Solver, Creationist.</subtitle><author><name>Vigneshwar Venkatachalapathi</name></author><entry><title type="html">A 24 year old’s struggle to learn Music</title><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/personal/experience/A-24yr-old's-struggle-to-learn-Music/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A 24 year old's struggle to learn Music" /><published>2017-04-22T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-04-22T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>https://themoralpanda.github.io/personal/experience/A%2024yr%20old's%20struggle%20to%20learn%20Music</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://themoralpanda.github.io/personal/experience/A-24yr-old's-struggle-to-learn-Music/">&lt;p&gt;Firstly listen to the below wonderful piece composed by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ludovicoeinaudi.com/&quot; title=&quot;Ludovico Einaudi&quot;&gt;Ludovico Einaudi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Courtesy of embedresponsively.com //--&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;responsive-video-container&quot;&gt;

  &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/X1DRDcGlSsE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you notice the talent? The involvement? The fingers moving effortlessly with absolute passion for the tune? The background orchestra supporting like pillars of a beautiful monument? The violins and cellos. This is a thing of a beauty. Now this is one beautiful example of a sincere and a passionate work. Isn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;I have a huge respect and admiration for artists and musicians. Because their work involves another dimension. A normal human being is engulfed in the worlds monotony and materialism and to his unluck and reality, he is involved in quest for money especially to support his family and himself. It is not his mistake. Not everybody is lucky to have an environment that supports following his or her passion. &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a 24 year old aspiring Keyboard student. The truth is, my family has a no background on Music or arts. My ancestors were mostly survivors. And to the almighty’s grace and my parents hardwork, I am in this position to atleast start learning now and to appreciate other things. My school days were comfortable but not too much. My parents struggled so much to put all the three of us in school and then into college, and they could not afford to think of anything beyond that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first came in touch with this Music and Keyboard in 8th grade, in Dr.RKV school, back in my native Sattur. That year, the school appointed a Music teacher, who came to the school twice in a week to teach some interested students, to play music. I was interested suddenly. I volunteered in my Extracurricular class and reached out to him. There was only one Keyboard in the school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He taught me, what is an Octave? He gave me the initial drawing with the letters. &lt;strong&gt;CDEFGABC&lt;/strong&gt;. After few weeks, he gave me the notes of the song &lt;strong&gt;“Suttum Vizhi Sudarae”__&lt;/strong&gt; from the movie &lt;strong&gt;“Ghajini”&lt;/strong&gt;, which was a huge hit song at that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile owing to my interest, My dad instantly ordered a Keyboard worth Rs.13000 and gifted me. He used to tell my mom, that “Playing music helps relax the mind and elevates one”. He has got a wonderful intellect and wisdom that is highly unique among parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I practised the notes for that song in the new keyboard and played it in front of my school, during the Annual day function at my school. Everyone appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There you go. I performed my first ever concert, right in the beginning of my learning. Even though its only one simple song. But heck yeah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that I was put in to the hostel and thats all. And things also changed at school. My music learning and interest started to diminish. I moved to another residential school for the higher secondary in another town, where the prime focus is on Board examinations. The keyboard was left in my native town, on top of the cupboard left for the rats to eat the thermocoal cups and the paper boxes, that surrounded my keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I came to college in chennai. The four years was absolutely wasted doing useless things. I almost forgot about music and keyboard. My keyboard was still in my native place. One day in my final year of college, suddenly it struck me. I was thinking about my keyboard and my music journey. I went in search of a Leather bag for keyboard and bought it in the city. And when I went back to my native, I was very lucky to find that my Keyboard was in good condition. Only the outer boxes have been terribly damaged by rats. The keyboard was little dirty but worked perfectly. And thanks to the rats coz they left the charger and its wire without eating. &lt;strong&gt;A hugh sigh of relief&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After two years, I joined a Keyboard class near my workplace. He taught me some basic keyboard music using Tamil classical raagams. He gave me notes in tamil. I learned it for 3 months. But then, I decided I have to change to western. Because working in IT sector, I might have to travel to different places at different point in time. So if I learn in Tamil notes, I might not be able to continue in other states or in other countries. So I joined another place. Its VJ school of Music in Chennai. They teach you western music. And its been 8 months since I have joined there. They teach you with a TRINITY international syllabus. And so far I am learning a lot. Its really good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its funny and pleasing to note, that most of the students who come to that school are below 10 years old. I even met a 4 year old who joined the keyboard class. The tutors used to continously ask him to press a button. The boy ends up smiling and looking around and rarely touchin the keyboard. But the most intersting part to note here is, the parents of those young kids are waiting outside of the classroom, looking through the glass walls, watching their children play something. And those kids even take some homework, which have be to completed before the next class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my close &lt;del&gt;friends&lt;/del&gt; is a Bharathanatyam dancer. She is a professional now. She has been training since she was a six year old. She used to often say me, how her mother used to push her to classes and force her to commit to learning the art. How much she was supporting her to perceive dance as a passion. I have watched my friend perform in a live show. I used to sit in awe with the colors and the lights and how my friend and her team performs. I always had a huge respect for artists. So she was an inspiration in that aspect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;And looking at these young children and their parents, I used to think, if my parents and relatives had any intersts or background, they would have motivated me right from my childhood. And I would be a true professional now, like my dancer friend. I would be doing professional shows and people would admire my work and I would be creating lovely pieces of music by now. &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But nevermind! People say, ** It’s never too late **. Its never too late to start some thing good. Its never too late to be grateful and persue some passionate work. I am pretty sure, I would become successful in future with my music. &lt;strong&gt;Because, I understand that I have deep soul driven intution and passion for music. And I have a huge respect for art and creativity.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes. My parents were not like those parents with music and art awareness. But they taught me some sincere dedication and kindness in persuing things. My mother taught me what is dedication, with her bhakthi and devotion to God. My father taught me wisdom and Gratitude which led to this current thought&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt; Its never too late&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I might be a beginner in playing music. But I am an expert in listening and appreciating Music. Because I believe in this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;__If you want to learn some art, the first step as a grown up, is to have respect towards arts and artists and then to commit and dedicate ourselves to it __&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My music education is going in parallel. But that doesn’t stop me from creating music. &lt;strong&gt;The below is a piece of Electron Dance MIX that I created recently&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Courtesy of embedresponsively.com //--&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;responsive-video-container&quot;&gt;

  &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Uf04dfaq9EU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S I also have some struggle in commiting as a grown up. So I will discuss on how I am overcame that in my next blog. Whatever happens, I am not gonna stop :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vigneshwar Venkatachalapathi</name></author><category term="Experience" /><category term="Motivation" /><category term="Introspection" /><summary type="html">Firstly listen to the below wonderful piece composed by Ludovico Einaudi</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What my mother taught me!</title><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/personal/philosophy/What-my-mother-taught-me!/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What my mother taught me!" /><published>2017-04-10T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-04-10T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>https://themoralpanda.github.io/personal/philosophy/What%20my%20mother%20taught%20me!</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://themoralpanda.github.io/personal/philosophy/What-my-mother-taught-me!/">&lt;p&gt;Sitting here in my office, an hour before breaking for Lunch, worrying about my hurtful past memories, I decided to call my mom. Its been quite a few days since I spoke to her. Although I don’t want to talk about my worrying thoughts, I just thought I could distract myself from the melancholic cloud, by talking to my mom. My mom proved yet again, she is one of a Kind. Its not like another ‘My Parents are the best’ post. In fact my Mother is very different. To tell about her in a nutshell, I can tell you the following habit of her and my Dad, that is so unique and different from most of the parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During our school days, all of us would have encountered an angry teacher saying &lt;strong&gt;Bring your parents tomorrow to meet me!&lt;/strong&gt; due to such situations, be it as a result of a small fight with our classmate, or some mischief. Especially if we are not completely meant to be blamed, Most of the parents would go there, protecting us. Some would go there, and try to apologize. But my mom, used to take me there and beat me, asking what did I do? She says, even if I am not completely responsible, I would have been responsible for some percent of the situation. So I used to get nicely from my teachers and then once again from my parents in front of the teachers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the point is, She always ensured, that I am doing clear. And that I am focused on introspecting myself and changing myself. Even if the events turn out difficult and even if some one does something to me, she ensured, that I am &lt;strong&gt;not reacting&lt;/strong&gt; with anger but with &lt;strong&gt;introspecting within myself, &lt;em&gt;over what I did and what I should not do&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. And that I believe was the key that helped me grow. I was lucky to have been taught that kind of approach. Okay. Lets me just list of the key good points that my mom followed and taught us to do. The point is not to boast that I have got the best mother in the world. But to share the key principles of my strong and noble mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When I came home crying, after one of my schoolmates, scolded me in a really bad word in &lt;strong&gt;6th grade&lt;/strong&gt;, She took me to the pooja room and asked me to promise, that I will never ever use such really bad words, never ever like my friend did. &lt;em&gt;First I confessed, that I also used to utter such words in school and I promised that I will never ever use it&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I was in a relationship with a girl for a long time. But that girl broke up with me brutally knowing her parents said a clear &lt;strong&gt;No&lt;/strong&gt; , for us because I belonged to a different caste. And the most important part is, she never ever said a Sorry. I was miserable. Deeply in depression for few months. And I was burning with anger that how could she do this such brutally without even asking a single sorry. My mother was next to me when she broke up with me, over a message. I was crying like hell. I was burning with anger. And I was shouting “I am gonna go to her family and say it out whatever happened between us. To slam their family bringing out the details! “. But my mother stopped me and she said this in Tamil. “ முள்ளு மேல சேலை விழுந்தாலும், சேலை மேல முள்ளு விழுந்தாலும், கிழியிறது சேலைதான்..இந்த கோவத்தை கட்டு படுத்து.. அந்த பொண்ணு உனக்கு என்ன பன்னிர்த்தாலும் சேரி.. விட்டுடு… கடவுள் பத்துகுருவாரு.
அவளும் அவள் குடும்பமும் நல்ல இருக்கட்டும்!
கோவத்தை விட்டுடு! உன்ன அழுச்சிடும்! “&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You would not believe how miserable I was at that moment. How desperate I was. The truth is, the girl ended it horribly. There was not even a single sorry in her face. Even though I am the victim of a serious event here, look at the words my mom said. Now compare it with my ex’s mom, whose first question to my ex about me is ,  “Is he a Brahmin?, before even asking my name and then the next word is “No. And she threw my photo away”!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My mother always believed and dedicated to God. Even if I come home claiming I got a seat in SSN College, she says “கடவுளுக்கு நன்றி சொல்லு”. And ask me to directly go to the pooja room and pray to thank.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust me! This thought of introspecting ourselves, this question of What I did and what I should not do, irrespective of what happens to us, is seriously important. Because, we all know that Change happens from within. We all know, we should take of our actions. But somehow, we end up with anger, misery and resentment. We react before we think. We worry about our image, because of our Ego.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And because of such wonderful ideals taught by my mom, I chased that girl who broke up with me, after 6 months and asked “Sorry myself”. And said, “என்னால உனக்கும் உன் குடும்பத்துக்கும் எதாவது பிரச்னை வந்திருந்த, என்ன மன்னிச்சுடு.” I said sorry and I wished her good luck, even after how she treated me. Because I felt guilty for, how she treated me. And after setting things straight, I can move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life is too short to be angry, to be grumpy, to be arrogant.
And most importantly “Knowing is not enough! We must apply. Willing is not enough! we must do”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vigneshwar Venkatachalapathi</name></author><category term="Philosophy" /><category term="Motivation" /><category term="Introspection" /><summary type="html">Sitting here in my office, an hour before breaking for Lunch, worrying about my hurtful past memories, I decided to call my mom. Its been quite a few days since I spoke to her. Although I don’t want to talk about my worrying thoughts, I just thought I could distract myself from the melancholic cloud, by talking to my mom. My mom proved yet again, she is one of a Kind. Its not like another ‘My Parents are the best’ post. In fact my Mother is very different. To tell about her in a nutshell, I can tell you the following habit of her and my Dad, that is so unique and different from most of the parents.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Musings of a broken heart!</title><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/The-Musings-of-a-broken-heart!/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Musings of a broken heart!" /><published>2017-04-04T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-04-04T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/The%20Musings%20of%20a%20broken%20heart!</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/The-Musings-of-a-broken-heart!/">&lt;p&gt;Ever wondered, what does a broken heart ponders about? How it struggles and learns to pick itself up, after falling terribly? How it goes through the random raids by past memories, both pleasant and miserable ones? How it constantly tries to erase those chains of images of both good and bad times? Especially when it knows, what it should do, how it should move on. While the world is full of cliche answers and clues, the experience of a heart is always unique. So even though it has numerous solution right at its hand, the suffering is always unique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/broken heart.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500px&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; alt=&quot;Page Image, Broken heart&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The context of this particular experience of a broken heart is of lost love. By the way, why does it got hurt in the first place? What does a heart essentially do, when it comes to love? It jumps to bond. It tries to be one, even though it knows, they are two different ones, both in terms of identity and in terms of ideals. The desperation often starts so successful, that it starts to believe that they both are made for each other. So you could imagine, like a pair of elements bonded together. And the universe is like a giant ball, inside which trillion pairs of elements roaming around. There are many different bonds among them. Some are double bonds, so strong, so powerful. Some are single bonds, one among the pair has bonded while the other is partially bonded. One is empowering and the other has got entangled. In some pairs, there are no bonds at all. But just roaming together without any affection between them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now, how does this heart react when its bond is broken, by the other element? It cries. It weeps. It wonders how the hell it could happen? It ponders why it did not happen? It struggles to see the present. Every song it hears, every pair it sees, this heart questions about what happened to itself? And the most important thing is, it wont be able to find an answer. People say, the reality is the answer. But why it happens for this little fellow? Everyone anticipate. Everyone wish for things. But why should this happen to this little heart? The world is full of wonderful bonds. But why does a strong bond which was wonderful, shatters into absolute mess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look at the complete timeline, of this hearts experience, right in the beginning is a lot of good times. Happy moments. Precious memories. But right after its beaten to its knees, it starts to focus on all the bad memories located in the end of the timeline. We cannot blame him completely. For the reality is that, its over. Even though it remembers the pleasant memories, it ponders over the miserable ones. The words uttered when it was dumped, starts whispering uncontrollably making him feel less alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The constant lies behind the reality. Most of the times, it fails to accept the reality. It struggles to understand its over. Essentially because, it started believing in miracles, right in the beginning of the timeline, when it was successfully able to bond. It slowly goes in to a limbo state where it constantly lies to itself, that miracle can once again happen. Things might get back to to how it was, in the beginning of the timeline. It only accepts that its over, when it sadly comes to know that the other heart has moved on. That one has bonded with somebody else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another huge struggle it shall go through, is to forgive or hate. If the mind advises him, to forget, he spit hate. If the mind asks him to hate her, he tries to forgive. Should the other one be really forgiven or not? Its a question that only reality can answer. But one important attribute of the reality is that, it is neutral. We can call it many names. Karma, Truth etc. Its neutral. It has got powers to make miracle happen once again. Or it can even cause the misery to the other one and make it realize the truth. But the unfortunate thing about this, the broken heart has no control over it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if both of them are really not meant to be together, then reality will definitely teach this broken fellow, to step up. To change the course. To feel motivated once again. To pick himself up. But if they are meant to be together, it will pull them both together, back again. Unfortunately, both these heart can’t know, whats going to happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever happens, I hope the reality will repair him and give him enough strength to walk once again. To fly once again. Because this heart doesn’t deserve anything less. And Life is far bigger than trillion musings.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vigneshwar Venkatachalapathi</name></author><category term="Philosophy" /><category term="Love" /><summary type="html">Ever wondered, what does a broken heart ponders about? How it struggles and learns to pick itself up, after falling terribly? How it goes through the random raids by past memories, both pleasant and miserable ones? How it constantly tries to erase those chains of images of both good and bad times? Especially when it knows, what it should do, how it should move on. While the world is full of cliche answers and clues, the experience of a heart is always unique. So even though it has numerous solution right at its hand, the suffering is always unique.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">To the perfect one month - April 2017</title><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/productivity/To-the-perfect-one-month-April-2017/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="To the perfect one month - April 2017" /><published>2017-03-31T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-03-31T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/productivity/To%20the%20perfect%20one%20month%20-%20April%202017</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/productivity/To-the-perfect-one-month-April-2017/">&lt;p&gt;Recently, I have been working a lot on improving my productivity and staying motivated on the goals. I already have a huge list of things to do. But I never have scheduled it properly, so that I have a weekly list or monthly Todo list. So I recently came up with a new idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been dreaming for a highly productive month for quite a long time. But even if I was able to complete few of my targets, I want to experience a perfect month. A month where you have completed all the set of targets that you have made, in its beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href=&quot;http://brendon.com/&quot;&gt;Brendon Burchard&lt;/a&gt; used to say
&amp;gt; “Focus goes out of the window, if there is no progress”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have created a list of all the prime targets that I need to complete in Next month, which begins tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I have decided to share it in the Social Media. Because,
1. “When you share a good schedule with your friends, there are two things that might happen, that will help us. 
    * They tend to talk about it and ask for updates, often. +Motivation
    * They tend to mock about it and questions every move. +Motivation_indeed
2. “Gives a right morale boost! just wat &lt;a href=&quot;http://themoralpanda.in&quot;&gt;The Moral Panda&lt;/a&gt; needs.
3. For tiny bit of social pressure, to complete what I have said. 
    * &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/rajni.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200px&quot; height=&quot;150px&quot; /&gt;
    * Sonna Vaaka Kaapathanum Pressure!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/To the perfect One month - April 2017.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;April 2017 plan - vicky&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;I will definitely achieve this!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I complete this, By 30th of April 2017 or 1st of May 2017 - I will blog about &lt;em&gt;How much I have done it!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this seems a nice idea, you can follow it to by creating ur list of goals.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vigneshwar Venkatachalapathi</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Intellectual" /><category term="Productivity" /><summary type="html">Recently, I have been working a lot on improving my productivity and staying motivated on the goals. I already have a huge list of things to do. But I never have scheduled it properly, so that I have a weekly list or monthly Todo list. So I recently came up with a new idea.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Stop waiting for the signs!</title><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/Stop-waiting-for-sings!/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stop waiting for the signs!" /><published>2016-11-23T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2016-11-23T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/Stop%20waiting%20for%20sings!</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/Stop-waiting-for-sings!/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*MqXKPc2jbuB_UQLn_kWoIg.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all have been waiting for signs. A sign from a universe or just an external
entity to kick us into starting something. An alarm, to learn a new thing or to
start a new project or to just move ahead. This waiting often leads to two
possible outcomes. Either we get a sign and start something or we stall so much
and the intention gets expired and idea runs out of frame. So how about
approaching this in a different way?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two important aspects of any (&lt;em&gt;Intention-Action-Completion&lt;/em&gt;) process, that we
often overlook are &lt;strong&gt;Clarity&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Progress&lt;/strong&gt;. Lets look at how these aspects
can be well utilized, in order to avoid the trap of waiting for an external
sign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*Clarity **essentially means a clear understanding of a subject. An important
aspect of clarity, is to have a fundamental perspective of whether the subject
is required or not, in the first case. Steve Jobs used to say *“ Deciding what
not to do is as important as deciding what to do”&lt;/em&gt;. So we should think,
understand and decide clearly, if our idea or intention is worth pursuing. Once
we have decided to purse, the next step would be to gather as much information
as possible. What is it? How to do it? Steps to do it? How others have done it?
What others failed to do it? Our understanding changes, every step as we gain
information. Our idea morphs in better shapes as we learn. Once we have a good
amount of information, the immediate step is to make a simple prototype as the
first level of action. &lt;a href=&quot;http://brendon.com/&quot;&gt;Brendon Burchard&lt;/a&gt; says&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Focus goes out of the window, if there is no progress”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prototyping shows progress. It shows that we are few steps ahead. It marks a
checkpoint. It even gives more information about the original idea, as we keep
learning. How it looks? How others see it? A prototype lets us, share our idea
to outside world and get feedback. This is the key ingredient of progress. So as
we prototype, learn, get feedback and iterate, we will move ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So instead of having an idea and waiting for some external signs, we can gain
information and start prototyping, to move ahead. Sometimes its just the start,
that is taking so much time. Collect more information. Look at whats already
there. Think about the boundaries. And if everything seems fine, just start.
Prototype and get feedback. Just do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://brendon.com/&quot;&gt;Brendon Burchard&lt;/a&gt; also talks about the Confidence vs
Competence loop. “The more you learn and become competent, the more you get
confident”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just start.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vigneshwar Venkatachalapathi</name></author><category term="Philosophy" /><category term="Intellectual" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Uncertainty of Life</title><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/The-Uncertainty-of-Life/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Uncertainty of Life" /><published>2016-08-03T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2016-08-03T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/The%20Uncertainty%20of%20Life</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/The-Uncertainty-of-Life/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*vE7cuy-_gfzwWvLHvRfyvw.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;figcaption_hack&quot;&gt;Its a choice!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever realized, how changing our lives are? If you look at our world, the only
word that describes it exactly, is “Change”. Everything is constantly changing.
Sometimes positively and sometimes negatively. It seriously seems like a roller
coaster ride. Leave the world. Look at us. Are we the same who we used to be? At
least, are we the one whom, we want to be? One moment we are so happy and
exuberant and on the other we are absolutely miserable. One of the noble truths
that the Great Buddha aka Gautama Siddhartha has informed the world is,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Life is like a river flowing on and on, ever-changing. Sometimes it flows
slowly and sometimes swiftly. It is smooth and gentle in some places, but later
on snags and rocks crop up out of nowhere. As soon as we think we are safe,
something unexpected happens” — The Buddha&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if Life by itself, is uncertain, how can we make our experiences, certain?
How can we continue being happy or increase the happiness streak? How can we
make sure, that our journey is going to be pleasant overall? These questions
have haunted me so far. So after reading messages of various philosophies, the
below is what I can sum up, as my understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The simple answer that I could say is “ We can’t. We can’t confirm that we are
safe. We can’t confirm, that whatever is yet to happen, is gonna be pleasant.
No. Seriously we can’t.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But, the only key that is available to us, is the way we handle them. Yes.
Seriously, we can. An emotion is always a reaction that is triggered to an
event. A feeling is a reaction to the emotion. An action is a reaction to a
feeling or a motive. So its always a reaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So indirectly, we have control. Not on what happens to us. But on how we handle
them. And the sweetest part of this, is the fact that it is our choice. Whatever
happens, we can either turn it into a fortune or get wounded. So at every
moment, every event, we have the choice. Even when something bad happens to us,
we have a choice. We can sit there and cry the crap out. Or we can find the best
thing that we can do, at that moment. Its always this moment that we have
control over. At this moment, how to be happy? What’s the best thing that we can
do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if we start doing our best at every moments, Its also a way of ensuring that
our experiences are pleasant. An experience is of two aspect. An event and an
impact. We have very less control over the events. We also have less control
over the impact. But we have absolutely 100% control on how to handle the
impact. So indirectly, we have control over the impact. So, that I believe, is
my understanding of this uncertainty aspect of Life and a simple approach to
handle it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vigneshwar Venkatachalapathi</name></author><category term="Philosophy" /><category term="Life" /><summary type="html">Its a choice!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why should women not drink? Especially in India?</title><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/society/Why-should-women-not-drink!-Especially-in-India!/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why should women not drink? Especially in India?" /><published>2016-01-26T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2016-01-26T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/society/Why%20should%20women%20not%20drink!%20Especially%20in%20India!</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/society/Why-should-women-not-drink!-Especially-in-India!/">&lt;p&gt;Recently, In a popular Tamil television channel program, where they debate on
various social topics, a discussion on Men’s perception on women happened. We
all know that this is huge argumentative topic that is around recently, in
India. In one episode, there was an argument that why Women can’t drink ? Its
their choice? Its their freedom?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would rather not call my below suggestion, an Answer to this question. But I
would instead, call it a perception. And I request all indian women, to think
about it, especially women of TamilNadu. Ok. So the question is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Why women should not drink and drug and party hard, like the way stupid Men do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;One line. &lt;strong&gt;Because you are precious to us.&lt;/strong&gt; I know this question is very
biased and it affects the fundamental freedom. Infact I agree, that both Men and
Women are equal and they have all rights and freedom to be who they really are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But you women! You guys are the precious jewels and pearls of our country. In
our rich Indian tradition, especially the Tamil culture, you guys are always the
best. Behind the success, behind the great achievements, behind every little
family , an Indian woman stands strong, holding things together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;we are saying that you belong there, the top level, the crown, especially in
tamilnadu. You guys are our Tamil Nadus treasure. And one more fact, there
happens a lot of crime because of drunk Men. The fact that, there are lot of
accidents, rapes and other utterly stupid stuff happening because of drunk
people in India, is so sad. And our government and people are already worried
about it so much and are trying desperately to solve that already existing
problem. So its your kind duty to help us get rid of the habit and become better
and not fight to become like us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So why do you guys want to come down from the level of diamonds to the level of
ground level carbons. Lets say you drink and drug and do things like that, but
you are our only hope. Women have the ability to change people and to make it a
better place. You can change a man from doing bad things. You can be the change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So thats why I believe you guys are requested not to drink and not to follow our
stupid habits. We want to you to remain strong and steady and help us become
clean and get rid of our habits. You are our hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the real question should be &lt;em&gt;why should not anyone drink&lt;/em&gt; ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friends drink, drug and party hard. So one day, I asked my dad, Why should I
not drink or drug? I am not causing any harm to anyone. Why cant I do that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;He said, when u drink or when u drug, you reach a totally different mental and
physical state, which is abnormal. Even though it gives you pleasure, it takes
you to different level, where you are loosing your real self. So the rule of
thumb is anything that takes you to abnormal dimension, is not healthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His answer was not biased. He didn’t say that I should not drink. He just said
its not healthy. In fact I understood, why would I desperately want to change my
state of being, to an abnormal dimension, where I am loosing my real self for a
petty pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So women, in our tamil culture, in India, you guys are very precious. You are
our hope. So please try to be in the level of jewels and helps us come out of
ground level carbon layer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S I am a **teetotaler. **I respect women so much. And I want them to help us. �No offence to people who drink or drug or party. Its clearly a suggestion.
Thanks.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vigneshwar Venkatachalapathi</name></author><category term="Women" /><category term="India" /><category term="Society" /><summary type="html">Recently, In a popular Tamil television channel program, where they debate on
various social topics, a discussion on Men’s perception on women happened. We
all know that this is huge argumentative topic that is around recently, in
India. In one episode, there was an argument that why Women can’t drink ? Its
their choice? Its their freedom?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">enum First_Ever (RoadTrip, Resort, Beach_rain, Bike_ride_in_rain_ECR )</title><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/personal/travel_diaries/enum-firstever-roadtrip-resort-beach_rain-bike_ride_in_rain_ecr-c/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="enum First_Ever (RoadTrip, Resort, Beach_rain, Bike_ride_in_rain_ECR )" /><published>2015-06-28T23:33:12+05:30</published><updated>2015-06-28T23:33:12+05:30</updated><id>https://themoralpanda.github.io/personal/travel_diaries/enum-firstever-roadtrip-resort-beach_rain-bike_ride_in_rain_ecr-c</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://themoralpanda.github.io/personal/travel_diaries/enum-firstever-roadtrip-resort-beach_rain-bike_ride_in_rain_ecr-c/">&lt;p&gt;Ever felt so happy and complete, after spending a beautiful day with wonderful friends and heading back home, listening to your favorite music? Yes! I had one of the best days of my life. Of course the title would give the best answer, to why my day was so special. It was a brilliant day which was actually planned clearly, the day before. This close friend of mine, Ajeeth Kumar, who is also my colleague at Infosys, invited me for this short trip.I accepted. Meanwhile, a whatsapp group was created and discussions about the trip were going on.&lt;img src=&quot;https://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2015/06/resort.jpg?w=300&quot; alt=&quot;resort&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guys have decided to assemble at Kelambakkam bus stop at exactly at 9 am, the next day.  I started a bit late at 7.50 am from Guduvanchery and reached the spot around 9.15 am. It seems that the guys were really hungry and they were having a sound breakfast, at a hotel near Kelambakkam bus stop. I joined in between and had a tasty Poori with Aloo masala. We were 8 in numbers. Myself, Nivi - a body builder working in CTS, Yeshwa - a perfect event organizer who is also working in CTS, Sundar - a little bulk dude who has become an assistant professor, Ajeeth kumar - a colleague of mine at Infosys, Rajkumar - a serious dude who entertains us 24X7 with this jokes and who is actually going to Delhi next week to pursue his IAS coaching, Raghav - a friend of Rajkumar and a CTS employee and Sricharan - a old looking but super cool engineer. we had four bikes, few pulsars and a busty bullet ! After the breakfast, we traveled to the final spot, the Jade resort.This is my first trip to a resort. Jade resort is a budget one, with limited facilities, such as few indoor games and outdoor games, a swimming pool, a restaurant and a pitch for volley ball and a small beach. Its actually worth the money that we paid them.&lt;img src=&quot;https://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2015/06/group-pic.jpg?w=300&quot; alt=&quot;group pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we reached the resort, we decided to start the day by playing Cricket. Actually AjeethKumar was late. So he came directly to the resort in his scooty. Yes ! He rode a scooty all the way from Saidapet to the resort via Thiruvanmayur. So we played Cricket for around two hours making jokes about each other and commenting at each other’s game. No one scored a good runs. We were spending most of our time searching for the ball, that we hit accidentally outside of the ground. Ultimately one of the shot threw the ball so far and so long that we actually lost it. Then we paid a fine amount of Rs.50 for the lost ball. Yes! we got little tired and so we decided to chill at the swimming pool. We got back to the office and had few rounds of free juice that they provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we moved to the pool area. Actually the Swimming pool keeper didnt allow us, with the kind of trousers that we had. He asked us to enter the pool only in nylon trousers. So Sundar and Ajeeth went outside and bought us all , a pair of nylon trousers. Then we entered the pool. We spent almost two hours in the water chilling and playing some interesting games. One among them was, ‘Searching The Coin’. A person will throw a coin in to the pool, while other guys remain closing the eyes or facing in the opposite direction.And once he threw the coin, the guys will search for it and the person who picks it up first, is the winner ! And none of us knew proper swimming. So we all practiced and learnt a bit. Two hours left and we took some selfies too. It was a complete fun. So we all got little hungry. So we came out of the pool and dressed up deciding to have Lunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually we came out of the resort, to a good hotel, to have lunch. The lunch was good. We started with few Soups and dove directly into the main items. We bought few Rotis and Subjis and fried rices too. An hour passed, with the loud burps beeping, we decided to finish. We actually have eaten for Rs.2000. But yes, It was worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we drove back to the resort and decided to play few indoor games. We started with Table Tennis and Snooker. None of us have played snooker before. So, as usual we started advising each other and commenting each others moves, in the game. It was total fun. But boy! the real snooker is far difficult to play when compared to the computer game. Meanwhile two among us, were playing Table Tennis. Now is the most interesting part. Some random family including a pretty young woman, came in to the sports arena and joined us to play Table Tennis. It was fun. I meant both the game and staring at the beautiful girl. It went almost few hours and then we decided to hand over the sports items at the office and we went to the beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2015/06/beach.jpg?w=300&quot; alt=&quot;beach&quot; /&gt;It was a simple but a lovely private beach. It was like heaven especially when the rain started pouring. These guys actually decided not to get into the sea and stayed in the shore playing Catch&amp;amp;Catch with a tennis ball brought by one of my friends. I actually decided to head on the sea and chill. I walked alone towards the water and decided to get my feet dipped in it. But then the waves were brilliant and that changed my mind. I decided to dip myself in completely. Slowing it started raining heavier. I laid on the edge of the shore, looking at the sky and slowly feeling the chill waves tickling on my feet. It was heaven. Trust me ! the best time to enjoy a beach is during chill rain and an awesome weather. The sea stood magnificent. I got this superb feeling that this is turning to be the one of the best days of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slowly we dragged ourselves out of the beach as it was getting late and reached the office. We waited there for few minutes, for the rain to come down, so that we could start our journey return. But the rain didn’t seem to come down. So we started from there. I was sitting behind Nivi, in his Pulsar. None of us rode at high speed. Instead we were riding at normal speeds, enjoying the visuals at either sides of the road. The rain got heavier. But boy it was brilliant. This is the first time, I am actually riding in a bike, in ECR, during rain and especially during an awesome weather. It was heaven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached the Kelambakkam bus stand. We were little hungry and decided to have a tea &lt;img src=&quot;https://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2015/06/dsc_0046.jpg?w=300&quot; alt=&quot;DSC_0046&quot; /&gt;and a sandwich. We were discussing how the day was and had few laughs at our memories that we gathered during our college days, especially about the girls whom we had crush on. Then I decided to take a bus from Kelambakkam to my place. Those guys continued their bike rides to their respective places. I got a bus to my place and on the way back, I was listening to my favorite musician A.R.Rahman’s ‘Ok Kanmani’ album. The weather was good and the music multiplied the joy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started feeling so good. So pinged all those guys saying a big thanks for hosting the trip and for inviting me especially. I pinged them that this was one of the best days of my life and it was because of them. I promised them that I will write a blog post about this today and will share it with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is that post !
This post is actually dedicated to all those guys ! [ Nivi, Ajeeth, Sundhar, Yeshwanth, Raghav, RajKumar ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much guys ! Love you loads ! :)
I simply can’t wait for the next trip to happen !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S -&amp;gt; I came home and talked to my dad. I told him that I had the best day of my life with the friends. He was happy. I told him that I should get a bike for me. I should roam around places and enjoy the world! He agreed and said “Yes ! pretty soon !”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to God too ! :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vigneshwar Venkatachalapathi</name></author><category term="Travel" /><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">Ever felt so happy and complete, after spending a beautiful day with wonderful friends and heading back home, listening to your favorite music? Yes! I had one of the best days of my life. Of course the title would give the best answer, to why my day was so special. It was a brilliant day which was actually planned clearly, the day before. This close friend of mine, Ajeeth Kumar, who is also my colleague at Infosys, invited me for this short trip.I accepted. Meanwhile, a whatsapp group was created and discussions about the trip were going on.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Stop The Goddamn Car !</title><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/stop-the-goddamn-car/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stop The Goddamn Car !" /><published>2015-06-17T11:05:10+05:30</published><updated>2015-06-17T11:05:10+05:30</updated><id>https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/stop-the-goddamn-car</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/stop-the-goddamn-car/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2015/06/cartoon-car-crash.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2015/06/cartoon-car-crash.jpg?w=300&quot; alt=&quot;Oh! Come On !&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Ever felt really bad after a stupid argument? over a stupid topic? with your close ones? Ever felt so exhausted after such bad moments and started to regret things? I also have encountered such moments. I recently got an important advice from my dad which was more like a solution to such kind of problems. So I thought I could share it with the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;He said ,&quot;The most important part of learning to drive a car, is knowing when to and how to stop the car&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I admired these words so much and tried to understand it better. An argument is carried through mood which is very dangerous.Because Mood in technical terms, is not a constant and is actually a variable. So it keeps on changing. So the way we react to situations and to the corresponding people, depends highly on the mood, that we possess at that point in time. So we should be very careful with our words and expressions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three kinds of people. One, who thinks 100% before taking a step. Two, who thinks,while taking a step. Three, who thinks, after taking a step. Of course the first kind are super intelligent. But most of us fall between the last two categories primarily because we can’t predict all such situations well ahead. But how can we pull ourselves out of the pit before falling deep? The car driving is a better example for such scenarios. There is a very thin margin between the moment you apply a break and the moment, an accident happens. The very act of arguing might lead to such situations too. Similar to the car driving scenario, there are two actors involved here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how to stop the car anyway?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily in the argument scenario, the margin is little bigger than that of the car scenario. The time you might get, to realize that an accident is about to happen is little larger. We would get a lot of clues that the argument, that we are having right now, might get a lot serious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I would like to call this point, in time as the &lt;strong&gt;Pinch point&lt;/strong&gt;. We can even take this literally. Right at this point we shall pinch ourselves and alert us that we should escape from this. The other clever options that we have is to ask for a &lt;strong&gt;Pause&lt;/strong&gt; ! a temporary stop in our argument and ask the target person some time before we can continue. Trust me the intensity will reduce for sure, the next time when u resume the argument. People will feel differently. The pace of it would have been reduced. The mood would have been changed. Time has the greatest power to change the mood. Give the argument, a break. And then resume it later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one simple way of avoiding such accidents in arguments, that I have learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S: I myself, is a beginner in following this new strategy. But I am sure, I would become good in due time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vigneshwar Venkatachalapathi</name></author><category term="Philosophy" /><category term="Ideas" /><category term="SelfImprovement" /><summary type="html">Ever felt really bad after a stupid argument? over a stupid topic? with your close ones? Ever felt so exhausted after such bad moments and started to regret things? I also have encountered such moments. I recently got an important advice from my dad which was more like a solution to such kind of problems. So I thought I could share it with the world.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Change within !</title><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/the-change-within/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Change within !" /><published>2015-04-25T16:55:10+05:30</published><updated>2015-04-25T16:55:10+05:30</updated><id>https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/the-change-within</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/the-change-within/">&lt;p&gt;“His character is so bad!”, “Such a nice person she is!”,”Hell knows, what a person he is! “.How many comments have we passed about other’s character?  How many times have we said “This is who I am!”,”That’s who she is!”?How many occasions, have we felt bad when somebody comments about our character or in general tries to describe about us to someone else? Well I am sure, I have done a lot of those mistakes and experienced a few from others.&lt;a href=&quot;https://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/character.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/character.jpg?w=300&quot; alt=&quot;Character&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am actually very afraid of books. I could clearly count the number of books that I have read so far. One is a Greek mythology based story and the other is a kid’s novel. But I had a different experience recently. Of course it’s my third book!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s &lt;strong&gt;‘Personality Development’ from Swami Vivekananda&lt;/strong&gt;. I started reading it because it’s got just 100 pages. In that book, there is one sentence that Swami Vivekananda exclaims about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;**Character is the repeated habits! And only repeated habits , alone can reform character**&quot;.

- **Swami Vivekananda **&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got so impressed at this quote! This is the only line that I remember from the entire book, now. I was thinking what he really meant, in this brilliant quote. Then I came up with a totally different perspective upon it. Let’s look at the statement once again for clarity. He has explained that character is actually the impressions that we create with our habits. So that means, &lt;strong&gt;there is a possibility for a change&lt;/strong&gt;! Of course the questions I have asked in the beginning of the post, is quite relevant to all of us. We are experiencing similar situations, in our day to day life. We are commenting about other’s character quite often. And we also have felt bad at different occasions, when somebody comments about us or to somebody else, which might be correct or sometimes not!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I sat down, thinking why do we comment about others character? Why does my team mate, say such things about me?Then after some time, I modified the question a bit, and thought how do people judge me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally realized that, my activities that I have demonstrated sometime and my behaviour that I express often made them think like that. Of course I am always interested in analyzing and improving me, because the &lt;strong&gt;opposite is not healthy and even virtually not possible&lt;/strong&gt;. So I concluded that the problem is partially on me too. Then I made my mind up and was further analyzing about my activities and the impressions that I create the positives and the negatives of them. In the end, I learned something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course the process of change is in progress for me. Wait! If this process is made in to a generic routine, everyone can use it! So I came up with below simple steps to change our character that Swami Vivekananda was exclaiming about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INTROSPECT YOURSELF&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;My father describes introspection like a scene and says “Bring the image of a court! You are the criminal and also the Judge. Now think in both the perspective and judge your action.” So analyse yourself and list down the opinions of others, which bother you.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;_&lt;Note&gt; Of course we can't consider every others opinion. List down, only from those that are close to you and from people who are precious to you._&lt;/Note&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;**FILTER **&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;From the list of opinions about your character, order them based on&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The reason for the opinion&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The possibility for a change.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE STUPID HABITS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This is the most important step. Write down the opinions on the left side .On the right side; write the list of your habits that cause those opinions.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FLIP THE BOARD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Try to flip the habits that cause those opinions, in a positive way.For instance:&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;_“Always angry”__- _Put a smile whenever you see them!&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Very silent”__-&lt;/em&gt; Go say Hi to the neighbour! Ask about the recent film that he has watched!&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;_“Jealous on someone”__- _call the same person and appreciate them!&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give it a try and you will be amazed, by how they see you there after! Trust me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no step 5! Because you are already a changed man!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt; &quot;But the most important point to remember here is, this is exactly how others feel too, when we comment about their character.&quot;  So let’s stop commenting on other's character because, it becomes out dated, when the target person has followed the steps.  Mind it!&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our character is what we make it! What we do! And it can be changed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vigneshwar Venkatachalapathi</name></author><category term="Ideas" /><category term="SelfImprovement" /><summary type="html">“His character is so bad!”, “Such a nice person she is!”,”Hell knows, what a person he is! “.How many comments have we passed about other’s character?  How many times have we said “This is who I am!”,”That’s who she is!”?How many occasions, have we felt bad when somebody comments about our character or in general tries to describe about us to someone else? Well I am sure, I have done a lot of those mistakes and experienced a few from others.</summary></entry></feed>
