<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-01-13T08:35:20+08:00</updated><id>https://themoralpanda.github.io//</id><title type="html">Vig Venkat</title><subtitle>Personal site of Vigneshwar Venkatachalapathi. Software Engineer, Blogger, Problem Solver, Creationist.</subtitle><author><name>Vig Venkat</name><email>haivicky@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Oxymorons in our Intentions!</title><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/society/Oxymorons-in-our-Intentions/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oxymorons in our Intentions!" /><published>2017-08-11T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-08-11T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/society/Oxymorons%20in%20our%20Intentions</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/society/Oxymorons-in-our-Intentions/">&lt;p&gt;Google defines an Oxymoron - a noun - a figure of speech in which apparently contradictory terms appear in conjunction (e.g. faith unfaithful kept him falsely true ). So Recently a thought came in to my mind. We as people exhibit a lot of oxymorons in our intentions. Below is a small collection of oxymorons in our intentions that I could remember. Please add on to this list. Its a funny one. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt; நீங்க தப்பா எடுத்துகலணா..நான் &lt;/u&gt; - We know clearly that they are going to thappa eduthufy, right after we say, what we are about to say. But still we do say it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;தெரியாம தான் கேக்குறேன்&lt;/u&gt; - Bloody hell! we are only therinjae asking. This is brutally sarcastic.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;நான் சொல்றத வச்சி என்ன எடை போடாத&lt;/u&gt; - I am gonna say whatever my mind shits. But make sure you dont judge me! Peace! :)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;If you don’t mind&lt;/u&gt; - Please don’t mind this. I need a favor.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;நான் அதை தப்புனு சொல்லள, ஆனா&lt;/u&gt; - Whatever you have done is wrong. Just change that god damn thing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;u&gt;நான் உன்னை குறை சொல்லள, ஆனா&lt;/u&gt; - Here is a ponnadai of ur stupid things you have done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all do this. More often really. We wanna do/say something. But we polish it and create a wonderful oxymoron in our intentions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vig Venkat</name><email>haivicky@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Ideas" /><category term="Social" /><category term="People" /><category term="Behaviours" /><summary type="html">Google defines an Oxymoron - a noun - a figure of speech in which apparently contradictory terms appear in conjunction (e.g. faith unfaithful kept him falsely true ). So Recently a thought came in to my mind. We as people exhibit a lot of oxymorons in our intentions. Below is a small collection of oxymorons in our intentions that I could remember. Please add on to this list. Its a funny one. :)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Completed listening to an Audio Book!</title><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/personal/experience/Completed-listening-to-an-Audio-Book/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Completed listening to an Audio Book!" /><published>2017-06-27T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-06-27T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://themoralpanda.github.io/personal/experience/Completed%20listening%20to%20an%20Audio%20Book</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://themoralpanda.github.io/personal/experience/Completed-listening-to-an-Audio-Book/">&lt;p&gt;Audio books are around quite a long time. But I got interested for the first time, after reading an email from Quincy Larson. FYI, Larson is the co-founder of Freecodecamp.com, an open and free learning site focused essentially on web development. Its very useful one. Larson owns a mailing list, via which he shares really useful contents such as, blogs about technology, success stories from freecodecamp users and occasionally about some interesting tech articles and book reviews. So in one of such mailers, he introduced an audio book called “The Fourth Transformation: How Augmented Reality &amp;amp; Artificial Intelligence will change Everything, By Robert Scoble, Shel Israel”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book is an eye opening book about how AI is the next big thing, in fact the current best thing. How AI will reach the world in multiple platforms and via various technologies right from HMD (Head mounted displays) to Wrist watches to further more pervasive technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He has mentioned as (5 hour listen) next to the title of the audio book, in that email. Instantly I got interested and followed by clicking on that link. It lead me to the Amazon’s audio book market place called, Audible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amazon’s Audible is the best audio book application+web store, that currently exist. Almost many book publishers started publishing an audio version of their popular old books and their latest ones via Audible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part about Audible, is the audio books are narrated by some decent narrators who have lend their voices narrating the book. So the point is, The books are read to you like how people read stories to their young children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact is Audible lets you try free for one month, though it collects your credit card information prior to it. Once you register, it will give you one credit which you can use it to download any book. Ideally a book cost 1 credit. The option available to us is that we can exchange the book anytime to download a new book, if we feel so. But the books we have completed, will be available to us completely, even if we cancel our subscription. After the free initial trial month, the subscription costs 15USD per month, which is roughly 970Rupees/month. It seems costly, but I feel its worth it, because of a different experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book about AI and Virtual Reality is not the first book for me to complete. When you sign up for the first time, the first book worth a credit, is free. So I signed up, downloading this AI book to my phone. Then in order to use the first month free trial, I used that extra credit, to buy another audio book. Its “The Power of Habit: Why we do what we do and how to change, by Charles Duhigg”. So I had two books in my phone and I was listening to it in parallel, switching between the two. This second book about habits is the one, I have finished listening to, first. So this is technically my first ever complete audio book experience. I will write a short review about that book in a separate blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Excellent audio quality plus a proper human narration instead of a robot voice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Complete audio book offline, split into multiple chapters was attractive.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;+30/-30 second forward/rewind was highly useful. Plus skipping chapters is also an option.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the most important thing with audio books was the experience. I am a person with very good memory. And after listening to chapter by chapter, slowly and steadily, I am able to clearly list down, what are the insights, from the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally when we read a book, we end up with a feel. But this audio book and the voices behind important passages reminds in your brain. At least for me. Its really good. Give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vig Venkat</name><email>haivicky@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Experience" /><category term="Productivity" /><summary type="html">Audio books are around quite a long time. But I got interested for the first time, after reading an email from Quincy Larson. FYI, Larson is the co-founder of Freecodecamp.com, an open and free learning site focused essentially on web development. Its very useful one. Larson owns a mailing list, via which he shares really useful contents such as, blogs about technology, success stories from freecodecamp users and occasionally about some interesting tech articles and book reviews. So in one of such mailers, he introduced an audio book called “The Fourth Transformation: How Augmented Reality &amp;amp; Artificial Intelligence will change Everything, By Robert Scoble, Shel Israel”.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Have I become rude and kindless recently?</title><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/personal/musing/Have-I-become-rude-and-kindless-recently/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Have I become rude and kindless recently?" /><published>2017-06-17T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-06-17T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://themoralpanda.github.io/personal/musing/Have%20I%20become%20rude%20and%20kindless%20recently</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://themoralpanda.github.io/personal/musing/Have-I-become-rude-and-kindless-recently/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;This is an argument within my self, on recent behaviour changes since Kailash trip, on may 2017. This content may be useless to other people. But some good points are there , if you have so much time. And reason to post it in my blog, hmm.. well its just a personal blog. I need not worry so much what others think 😀 &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/RecentRudeness.png&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; alt=&quot;An Argument with myself&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vig Venkat</name><email>haivicky@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Musing" /><category term="Thoughts" /><summary type="html">This is an argument within my self, on recent behaviour changes since Kailash trip, on may 2017. This content may be useless to other people. But some good points are there , if you have so much time. And reason to post it in my blog, hmm.. well its just a personal blog. I need not worry so much what others think 😀</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Here is why I am losing interests on my country and I dont need help</title><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/opinion/society/Here-is-why-I-am-losing-interests-in-my-country-and-I-don't-need-help!/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Here is why I am losing interests on my country and I dont need help" /><published>2017-06-13T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-06-13T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://themoralpanda.github.io/opinion/society/Here%20is%20why%20I%20am%20losing%20interests%20in%20my%20country%20and%20I%20don't%20need%20help!</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://themoralpanda.github.io/opinion/society/Here-is-why-I-am-losing-interests-in-my-country-and-I-don't-need-help!/">&lt;p&gt;I am an Indian. A 24 year old. Spent all my 24 years so far in India except few vacations. Right through my school days, I was taught Patriotism via books, Prayers, Sports routines and early celebrations of historically important days. During those days, I felt it. The pride, the energy and the importance. But as I grew up and became an adult and especially after the arrival of the social media, I am slowly feeling the reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not loosing interests because of Government. Because, they are doing what they have been doing and they will be doing the same. So Never mind!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its not because of the Celebrities either. They are also doing the same thing that they have been doing all the time. Pretending to be a beacon at the sea shore but flickering like a useless street lamp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am annoyed because of the People. I am loosing patriotism because of the my brothers and sisters out there. The People. Here is why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People ask for “No Reservation!”. But they don’t fight for “No Castes”. Because No Reservation means all people are equal. Then why not fight for “No Caste” as a whole. If people are so proud of who they are and what caste they belong to, how can they ask for “No Reservation”, which ultimately says, that all people are equal.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One religion accuses other religion of spreading their religion. But they themselves post, “In order to have a beautiful life, say the mantras of this God”, in almost all the MTC buses.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And the children are becoming desperate when it comes to Love. And the parents are becoming desperate when it comes to Marriage.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Epic pilgrimages underwent. Infinite discourses about God, has been spread. Truck load of comments about the society. Yet, people don’t stop commenting about others values.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The same actor, who talks great about, women and respect towards them, dances for an item song, in every fucking movie.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One week before, they accuse him of knowing nothing about politics and condemns him from entering in to politics, and exactly one week later, call him “Thalaivaaaa” posting a picture from his upcoming movie.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some build apartments in every little lakes. Many buy a comfortable home in the same apartment. And all complain about water scarcity and Government’s measures on it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They say, discrimination of any form, is an offense. But all discrimination of all kinds, happens inside the homes. They can’t even stand up against their own parent’s societal values.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A single person drives a Sedan alone, daily to office, and complains about Pollution in the city.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They worry so much about U.S coming out of Paris climate change treaty, but continue cutting trees and conquer lakes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A cow is an holy animal whereas a chicken is a Satan’s curse.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If animals know about the purspose of dustbins, then I bet that they would not throw away anything on the roads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lists goes on and on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real change that is required in India, is the change in people’s mind.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vig Venkat</name><email>haivicky@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Opinions" /><category term="Society" /><category term="Musing" /><summary type="html">I am an Indian. A 24 year old. Spent all my 24 years so far in India except few vacations. Right through my school days, I was taught Patriotism via books, Prayers, Sports routines and early celebrations of historically important days. During those days, I felt it. The pride, the energy and the importance. But as I grew up and became an adult and especially after the arrival of the social media, I am slowly feeling the reality.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A 24 year old’s struggle to learn Music</title><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/personal/experience/A-24yr-old's-struggle-to-learn-Music/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A 24 year old's struggle to learn Music" /><published>2017-04-22T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-04-22T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://themoralpanda.github.io/personal/experience/A%2024yr%20old's%20struggle%20to%20learn%20Music</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://themoralpanda.github.io/personal/experience/A-24yr-old's-struggle-to-learn-Music/">&lt;p&gt;Firstly listen to the below wonderful piece composed by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ludovicoeinaudi.com/&quot; title=&quot;Ludovico Einaudi&quot;&gt;Ludovico Einaudi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Courtesy of embedresponsively.com //--&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;responsive-video-container&quot;&gt;

  &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/X1DRDcGlSsE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you notice the talent? The involvement? The fingers moving effortlessly with absolute passion for the tune? The background orchestra supporting like pillars of a beautiful monument? The violins and cellos. This is a thing of a beauty. Now this is one beautiful example of a sincere and a passionate work. Isn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;I have a huge respect and admiration for artists and musicians. Because their work involves another dimension. A normal human being is engulfed in the worlds monotony and materialism and to his unluck and reality, he is involved in quest for money especially to support his family and himself. It is not his mistake. Not everybody is lucky to have an environment that supports following his or her passion. &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a 24 year old aspiring Keyboard student. The truth is, my family has a no background on Music or arts. My ancestors were mostly survivors. And to the almighty’s grace and my parents hardwork, I am in this position to atleast start learning now and to appreciate other things. My school days were comfortable but not too much. My parents struggled so much to put all the three of us in school and then into college, and they could not afford to think of anything beyond that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first came in touch with this Music and Keyboard in 8th grade, in Dr.RKV school, back in my native Sattur. That year, the school appointed a Music teacher, who came to the school twice in a week to teach some interested students, to play music. I was interested suddenly. I volunteered in my Extracurricular class and reached out to him. There was only one Keyboard in the school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He taught me, what is an Octave? He gave me the initial drawing with the letters. &lt;strong&gt;CDEFGABC&lt;/strong&gt;. After few weeks, he gave me the notes of the song &lt;strong&gt;“Suttum Vizhi Sudarae”__&lt;/strong&gt; from the movie &lt;strong&gt;“Ghajini”&lt;/strong&gt;, which was a huge hit song at that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile owing to my interest, My dad instantly ordered a Keyboard worth Rs.13000 and gifted me. He used to tell my mom, that “Playing music helps relax the mind and elevates one”. He has got a wonderful intellect and wisdom that is highly unique among parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I practised the notes for that song in the new keyboard and played it in front of my school, during the Annual day function at my school. Everyone appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There you go. I performed my first ever concert, right in the beginning of my learning. Even though its only one simple song. But heck yeah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that I was put in to the hostel and thats all. And things also changed at school. My music learning and interest started to diminish. I moved to another residential school for the higher secondary in another town, where the prime focus is on Board examinations. The keyboard was left in my native town, on top of the cupboard left for the rats to eat the thermocoal cups and the paper boxes, that surrounded my keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I came to college in chennai. The four years was absolutely wasted doing useless things. I almost forgot about music and keyboard. My keyboard was still in my native place. One day in my final year of college, suddenly it struck me. I was thinking about my keyboard and my music journey. I went in search of a Leather bag for keyboard and bought it in the city. And when I went back to my native, I was very lucky to find that my Keyboard was in good condition. Only the outer boxes have been terribly damaged by rats. The keyboard was little dirty but worked perfectly. And thanks to the rats coz they left the charger and its wire without eating. &lt;strong&gt;A hugh sigh of relief&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After two years, I joined a Keyboard class near my workplace. He taught me some basic keyboard music using Tamil classical raagams. He gave me notes in tamil. I learned it for 3 months. But then, I decided I have to change to western. Because working in IT sector, I might have to travel to different places at different point in time. So if I learn in Tamil notes, I might not be able to continue in other states or in other countries. So I joined another place. Its VJ school of Music in Chennai. They teach you western music. And its been 8 months since I have joined there. They teach you with a TRINITY international syllabus. And so far I am learning a lot. Its really good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its funny and pleasing to note, that most of the students who come to that school are below 10 years old. I even met a 4 year old who joined the keyboard class. The tutors used to continously ask him to press a button. The boy ends up smiling and looking around and rarely touchin the keyboard. But the most intersting part to note here is, the parents of those young kids are waiting outside of the classroom, looking through the glass walls, watching their children play something. And those kids even take some homework, which have be to completed before the next class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my close &lt;del&gt;friends&lt;/del&gt; is a Bharathanatyam dancer. She is a professional now. She has been training since she was a six year old. She used to often say me, how her mother used to push her to classes and force her to commit to learning the art. How much she was supporting her to perceive dance as a passion. I have watched my friend perform in a live show. I used to sit in awe with the colors and the lights and how my friend and her team performs. I always had a huge respect for artists. So she was an inspiration in that aspect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;And looking at these young children and their parents, I used to think, if my parents and relatives had any intersts or background, they would have motivated me right from my childhood. And I would be a true professional now, like my dancer friend. I would be doing professional shows and people would admire my work and I would be creating lovely pieces of music by now. &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But nevermind! People say, ** It’s never too late **. Its never too late to start some thing good. Its never too late to be grateful and persue some passionate work. I am pretty sure, I would become successful in future with my music. &lt;strong&gt;Because, I understand that I have deep soul driven intution and passion for music. And I have a huge respect for art and creativity.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes. My parents were not like those parents with music and art awareness. But they taught me some sincere dedication and kindness in persuing things. My mother taught me what is dedication, with her bhakthi and devotion to God. My father taught me wisdom and Gratitude which led to this current thought&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt; Its never too late&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I might be a beginner in playing music. But I am an expert in listening and appreciating Music. Because I believe in this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;__If you want to learn some art, the first step as a grown up, is to have respect towards arts and artists and then to commit and dedicate ourselves to it __&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My music education is going in parallel. But that doesn’t stop me from creating music. &lt;strong&gt;The below is a piece of Electron Dance MIX that I created recently&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Courtesy of embedresponsively.com //--&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;responsive-video-container&quot;&gt;

  &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Uf04dfaq9EU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S I also have some struggle in commiting as a grown up. So I will discuss on how I am overcame that in my next blog. Whatever happens, I am not gonna stop :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vig Venkat</name><email>haivicky@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Experience" /><category term="Motivation" /><category term="Introspection" /><summary type="html">Firstly listen to the below wonderful piece composed by Ludovico Einaudi</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What my mother taught me!</title><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/personal/philosophy/What-my-mother-taught-me!/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What my mother taught me!" /><published>2017-04-10T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-04-10T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://themoralpanda.github.io/personal/philosophy/What%20my%20mother%20taught%20me!</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://themoralpanda.github.io/personal/philosophy/What-my-mother-taught-me!/">&lt;p&gt;Sitting here in my office, an hour before breaking for Lunch, worrying about my hurtful past memories, I decided to call my mom. Its been quite a few days since I spoke to her. Although I don’t want to talk about my worrying thoughts, I just thought I could distract myself from the melancholic cloud, by talking to my mom. My mom proved yet again, she is one of a Kind. Its not like another ‘My Parents are the best’ post. In fact my Mother is very different. To tell about her in a nutshell, I can tell you the following habit of her and my Dad, that is so unique and different from most of the parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During our school days, all of us would have encountered an angry teacher saying &lt;strong&gt;Bring your parents tomorrow to meet me!&lt;/strong&gt; due to such situations, be it as a result of a small fight with our classmate, or some mischief. Especially if we are not completely meant to be blamed, Most of the parents would go there, protecting us. Some would go there, and try to apologize. But my mom, used to take me there and beat me, asking what did I do? She says, even if I am not completely responsible, I would have been responsible for some percent of the situation. So I used to get nicely from my teachers and then once again from my parents in front of the teachers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the point is, She always ensured, that I am doing clear. And that I am focused on introspecting myself and changing myself. Even if the events turn out difficult and even if some one does something to me, she ensured, that I am &lt;strong&gt;not reacting&lt;/strong&gt; with anger but with &lt;strong&gt;introspecting within myself, &lt;em&gt;over what I did and what I should not do&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. And that I believe was the key that helped me grow. I was lucky to have been taught that kind of approach. Okay. Lets me just list of the key good points that my mom followed and taught us to do. The point is not to boast that I have got the best mother in the world. But to share the key principles of my strong and noble mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When I came home crying, after one of my schoolmates, scolded me in a really bad word in &lt;strong&gt;6th grade&lt;/strong&gt;, She took me to the pooja room and asked me to promise, that I will never ever use such really bad words, never ever like my friend did. &lt;em&gt;First I confessed, that I also used to utter such words in school and I promised that I will never ever use it&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I was in a relationship with a girl for a long time. But that girl broke up with me brutally knowing her parents said a clear &lt;strong&gt;No&lt;/strong&gt; , for us because I belonged to a different caste. And the most important part is, she never ever said a Sorry. I was miserable. Deeply in depression for few months. And I was burning with anger that how could she do this such brutally without even asking a single sorry. My mother was next to me when she broke up with me, over a message. I was crying like hell. I was burning with anger. And I was shouting “I am gonna go to her family and say it out whatever happened between us. To slam their family bringing out the details! “. But my mother stopped me and she said this in Tamil. “ முள்ளு மேல சேலை விழுந்தாலும், சேலை மேல முள்ளு விழுந்தாலும், கிழியிறது சேலைதான்..இந்த கோவத்தை கட்டு படுத்து.. அந்த பொண்ணு உனக்கு என்ன பன்னிர்த்தாலும் சேரி.. விட்டுடு… கடவுள் பத்துகுருவாரு.
அவளும் அவள் குடும்பமும் நல்ல இருக்கட்டும்!
கோவத்தை விட்டுடு! உன்ன அழுச்சிடும்! “&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You would not believe how miserable I was at that moment. How desperate I was. The truth is, the girl ended it horribly. There was not even a single sorry in her face. Even though I am the victim of a serious event here, look at the words my mom said. Now compare it with my ex’s mom, whose first question to my ex about me is ,  “Is he a Brahmin?, before even asking my name and then the next word is “No. And she threw my photo away”!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;My mother always believed and dedicated to God. Even if I come home claiming I got a seat in SSN College, she says “கடவுளுக்கு நன்றி சொல்லு”. And ask me to directly go to the pooja room and pray to thank.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust me! This thought of introspecting ourselves, this question of What I did and what I should not do, irrespective of what happens to us, is seriously important. Because, we all know that Change happens from within. We all know, we should take of our actions. But somehow, we end up with anger, misery and resentment. We react before we think. We worry about our image, because of our Ego.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And because of such wonderful ideals taught by my mom, I chased that girl who broke up with me, after 6 months and asked “Sorry myself”. And said, “என்னால உனக்கும் உன் குடும்பத்துக்கும் எதாவது பிரச்னை வந்திருந்த, என்ன மன்னிச்சுடு.” I said sorry and I wished her good luck, even after how she treated me. Because I felt guilty for, how she treated me. And after setting things straight, I can move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life is too short to be angry, to be grumpy, to be arrogant.
And most importantly “Knowing is not enough! We must apply. Willing is not enough! we must do”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vig Venkat</name><email>haivicky@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Philosophy" /><category term="Motivation" /><category term="Introspection" /><summary type="html">Sitting here in my office, an hour before breaking for Lunch, worrying about my hurtful past memories, I decided to call my mom. Its been quite a few days since I spoke to her. Although I don’t want to talk about my worrying thoughts, I just thought I could distract myself from the melancholic cloud, by talking to my mom. My mom proved yet again, she is one of a Kind. Its not like another ‘My Parents are the best’ post. In fact my Mother is very different. To tell about her in a nutshell, I can tell you the following habit of her and my Dad, that is so unique and different from most of the parents.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Musings of a broken heart!</title><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/The-Musings-of-a-broken-heart!/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Musings of a broken heart!" /><published>2017-04-04T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-04-04T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/The%20Musings%20of%20a%20broken%20heart!</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/The-Musings-of-a-broken-heart!/">&lt;p&gt;Ever wondered, what does a broken heart ponders about? How it struggles and learns to pick itself up, after falling terribly? How it goes through the random raids by past memories, both pleasant and miserable ones? How it constantly tries to erase those chains of images of both good and bad times? Especially when it knows, what it should do, how it should move on. While the world is full of cliche answers and clues, the experience of a heart is always unique. So even though it has numerous solution right at its hand, the suffering is always unique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/broken heart.jpg&quot; width=&quot;500px&quot; height=&quot;300px&quot; itemprop=&quot;image&quot; alt=&quot;Page Image, Broken heart&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The context of this particular experience of a broken heart is of lost love. By the way, why does it got hurt in the first place? What does a heart essentially do, when it comes to love? It jumps to bond. It tries to be one, even though it knows, they are two different ones, both in terms of identity and in terms of ideals. The desperation often starts so successful, that it starts to believe that they both are made for each other. So you could imagine, like a pair of elements bonded together. And the universe is like a giant ball, inside which trillion pairs of elements roaming around. There are many different bonds among them. Some are double bonds, so strong, so powerful. Some are single bonds, one among the pair has bonded while the other is partially bonded. One is empowering and the other has got entangled. In some pairs, there are no bonds at all. But just roaming together without any affection between them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now, how does this heart react when its bond is broken, by the other element? It cries. It weeps. It wonders how the hell it could happen? It ponders why it did not happen? It struggles to see the present. Every song it hears, every pair it sees, this heart questions about what happened to itself? And the most important thing is, it wont be able to find an answer. People say, the reality is the answer. But why it happens for this little fellow? Everyone anticipate. Everyone wish for things. But why should this happen to this little heart? The world is full of wonderful bonds. But why does a strong bond which was wonderful, shatters into absolute mess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you look at the complete timeline, of this hearts experience, right in the beginning is a lot of good times. Happy moments. Precious memories. But right after its beaten to its knees, it starts to focus on all the bad memories located in the end of the timeline. We cannot blame him completely. For the reality is that, its over. Even though it remembers the pleasant memories, it ponders over the miserable ones. The words uttered when it was dumped, starts whispering uncontrollably making him feel less alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The constant lies behind the reality. Most of the times, it fails to accept the reality. It struggles to understand its over. Essentially because, it started believing in miracles, right in the beginning of the timeline, when it was successfully able to bond. It slowly goes in to a limbo state where it constantly lies to itself, that miracle can once again happen. Things might get back to to how it was, in the beginning of the timeline. It only accepts that its over, when it sadly comes to know that the other heart has moved on. That one has bonded with somebody else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another huge struggle it shall go through, is to forgive or hate. If the mind advises him, to forget, he spit hate. If the mind asks him to hate her, he tries to forgive. Should the other one be really forgiven or not? Its a question that only reality can answer. But one important attribute of the reality is that, it is neutral. We can call it many names. Karma, Truth etc. Its neutral. It has got powers to make miracle happen once again. Or it can even cause the misery to the other one and make it realize the truth. But the unfortunate thing about this, the broken heart has no control over it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if both of them are really not meant to be together, then reality will definitely teach this broken fellow, to step up. To change the course. To feel motivated once again. To pick himself up. But if they are meant to be together, it will pull them both together, back again. Unfortunately, both these heart can’t know, whats going to happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever happens, I hope the reality will repair him and give him enough strength to walk once again. To fly once again. Because this heart doesn’t deserve anything less. And Life is far bigger than trillion musings.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vig Venkat</name><email>haivicky@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Philosophy" /><category term="Love" /><summary type="html">Ever wondered, what does a broken heart ponders about? How it struggles and learns to pick itself up, after falling terribly? How it goes through the random raids by past memories, both pleasant and miserable ones? How it constantly tries to erase those chains of images of both good and bad times? Especially when it knows, what it should do, how it should move on. While the world is full of cliche answers and clues, the experience of a heart is always unique. So even though it has numerous solution right at its hand, the suffering is always unique.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">To the perfect one month - April 2017</title><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/productivity/To-the-perfect-one-month-April-2017/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="To the perfect one month - April 2017" /><published>2017-03-31T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-03-31T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/productivity/To%20the%20perfect%20one%20month%20-%20April%202017</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/productivity/To-the-perfect-one-month-April-2017/">&lt;p&gt;Recently, I have been working a lot on improving my productivity and staying motivated on the goals. I already have a huge list of things to do. But I never have scheduled it properly, so that I have a weekly list or monthly Todo list. So I recently came up with a new idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been dreaming for a highly productive month for quite a long time. But even if I was able to complete few of my targets, I want to experience a perfect month. A month where you have completed all the set of targets that you have made, in its beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href=&quot;http://brendon.com/&quot;&gt;Brendon Burchard&lt;/a&gt; used to say
&amp;gt; “Focus goes out of the window, if there is no progress”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have created a list of all the prime targets that I need to complete in Next month, which begins tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I have decided to share it in the Social Media. Because,
1. “When you share a good schedule with your friends, there are two things that might happen, that will help us. 
    * They tend to talk about it and ask for updates, often. +Motivation
    * They tend to mock about it and questions every move. +Motivation_indeed
2. “Gives a right morale boost! just wat &lt;a href=&quot;http://themoralpanda.in&quot;&gt;The Moral Panda&lt;/a&gt; needs.
3. For tiny bit of social pressure, to complete what I have said. 
    * &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/rajni.jpg&quot; width=&quot;200px&quot; height=&quot;150px&quot; /&gt;
    * Sonna Vaaka Kaapathanum Pressure!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/To the perfect One month - April 2017.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;April 2017 plan - vicky&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;I will definitely achieve this!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I complete this, By 30th of April 2017 or 1st of May 2017 - I will blog about &lt;em&gt;How much I have done it!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this seems a nice idea, you can follow it to by creating ur list of goals.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vig Venkat</name><email>haivicky@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Intellectual" /><category term="Productivity" /><summary type="html">Recently, I have been working a lot on improving my productivity and staying motivated on the goals. I already have a huge list of things to do. But I never have scheduled it properly, so that I have a weekly list or monthly Todo list. So I recently came up with a new idea.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Stop waiting for the signs!</title><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/Stop-waiting-for-sings!/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stop waiting for the signs!" /><published>2016-11-23T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2016-11-23T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/Stop%20waiting%20for%20sings!</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/Stop-waiting-for-sings!/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*MqXKPc2jbuB_UQLn_kWoIg.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all have been waiting for signs. A sign from a universe or just an external
entity to kick us into starting something. An alarm, to learn a new thing or to
start a new project or to just move ahead. This waiting often leads to two
possible outcomes. Either we get a sign and start something or we stall so much
and the intention gets expired and idea runs out of frame. So how about
approaching this in a different way?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two important aspects of any (&lt;em&gt;Intention-Action-Completion&lt;/em&gt;) process, that we
often overlook are &lt;strong&gt;Clarity&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Progress&lt;/strong&gt;. Lets look at how these aspects
can be well utilized, in order to avoid the trap of waiting for an external
sign.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*Clarity **essentially means a clear understanding of a subject. An important
aspect of clarity, is to have a fundamental perspective of whether the subject
is required or not, in the first case. Steve Jobs used to say *“ Deciding what
not to do is as important as deciding what to do”&lt;/em&gt;. So we should think,
understand and decide clearly, if our idea or intention is worth pursuing. Once
we have decided to purse, the next step would be to gather as much information
as possible. What is it? How to do it? Steps to do it? How others have done it?
What others failed to do it? Our understanding changes, every step as we gain
information. Our idea morphs in better shapes as we learn. Once we have a good
amount of information, the immediate step is to make a simple prototype as the
first level of action. &lt;a href=&quot;http://brendon.com/&quot;&gt;Brendon Burchard&lt;/a&gt; says&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Focus goes out of the window, if there is no progress”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prototyping shows progress. It shows that we are few steps ahead. It marks a
checkpoint. It even gives more information about the original idea, as we keep
learning. How it looks? How others see it? A prototype lets us, share our idea
to outside world and get feedback. This is the key ingredient of progress. So as
we prototype, learn, get feedback and iterate, we will move ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So instead of having an idea and waiting for some external signs, we can gain
information and start prototyping, to move ahead. Sometimes its just the start,
that is taking so much time. Collect more information. Look at whats already
there. Think about the boundaries. And if everything seems fine, just start.
Prototype and get feedback. Just do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://brendon.com/&quot;&gt;Brendon Burchard&lt;/a&gt; also talks about the Confidence vs
Competence loop. “The more you learn and become competent, the more you get
confident”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just start.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vig Venkat</name><email>haivicky@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Philosophy" /><category term="Intellectual" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Uncertainty of Life</title><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/The-Uncertainty-of-Life/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Uncertainty of Life" /><published>2016-08-03T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2016-08-03T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/The%20Uncertainty%20of%20Life</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/The-Uncertainty-of-Life/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*vE7cuy-_gfzwWvLHvRfyvw.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;figcaption_hack&quot;&gt;Its a choice!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever realized, how changing our lives are? If you look at our world, the only
word that describes it exactly, is “Change”. Everything is constantly changing.
Sometimes positively and sometimes negatively. It seriously seems like a roller
coaster ride. Leave the world. Look at us. Are we the same who we used to be? At
least, are we the one whom, we want to be? One moment we are so happy and
exuberant and on the other we are absolutely miserable. One of the noble truths
that the Great Buddha aka Gautama Siddhartha has informed the world is,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Life is like a river flowing on and on, ever-changing. Sometimes it flows
slowly and sometimes swiftly. It is smooth and gentle in some places, but later
on snags and rocks crop up out of nowhere. As soon as we think we are safe,
something unexpected happens” — The Buddha&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if Life by itself, is uncertain, how can we make our experiences, certain?
How can we continue being happy or increase the happiness streak? How can we
make sure, that our journey is going to be pleasant overall? These questions
have haunted me so far. So after reading messages of various philosophies, the
below is what I can sum up, as my understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The simple answer that I could say is “ We can’t. We can’t confirm that we are
safe. We can’t confirm, that whatever is yet to happen, is gonna be pleasant.
No. Seriously we can’t.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But, the only key that is available to us, is the way we handle them. Yes.
Seriously, we can. An emotion is always a reaction that is triggered to an
event. A feeling is a reaction to the emotion. An action is a reaction to a
feeling or a motive. So its always a reaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So indirectly, we have control. Not on what happens to us. But on how we handle
them. And the sweetest part of this, is the fact that it is our choice. Whatever
happens, we can either turn it into a fortune or get wounded. So at every
moment, every event, we have the choice. Even when something bad happens to us,
we have a choice. We can sit there and cry the crap out. Or we can find the best
thing that we can do, at that moment. Its always this moment that we have
control over. At this moment, how to be happy? What’s the best thing that we can
do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if we start doing our best at every moments, Its also a way of ensuring that
our experiences are pleasant. An experience is of two aspect. An event and an
impact. We have very less control over the events. We also have less control
over the impact. But we have absolutely 100% control on how to handle the
impact. So indirectly, we have control over the impact. So, that I believe, is
my understanding of this uncertainty aspect of Life and a simple approach to
handle it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vig Venkat</name><email>haivicky@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Philosophy" /><category term="Life" /><summary type="html">Its a choice!</summary></entry></feed>
