<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-03-22T22:46:20+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000//</id><title type="html">The Moral Panda</title><subtitle>Blog site of Vigneshwar Venkatachalapathi</subtitle><author><name>Vigneshwar Venkatachalapathi</name></author><entry><title type="html">enum First_Ever (RoadTrip, Resort, Beach_rain, Bike_ride_in_rain_ECR )</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/personal/travel_diaries/enum-firstever-roadtrip-resort-beach_rain-bike_ride_in_rain_ecr-c/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="enum First_Ever (RoadTrip, Resort, Beach_rain, Bike_ride_in_rain_ECR )" /><published>2015-06-28T23:33:12+05:30</published><updated>2015-06-28T23:33:12+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/personal/travel_diaries/enum-firstever-roadtrip-resort-beach_rain-bike_ride_in_rain_ecr-c</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/personal/travel_diaries/enum-firstever-roadtrip-resort-beach_rain-bike_ride_in_rain_ecr-c/">&lt;p&gt;Ever felt so happy and complete, after spending a beautiful day with wonderful friends and heading back home, listening to your favorite music? Yes! I had one of the best days of my life. Of course the title would give the best answer, to why my day was so special. It was a brilliant day which was actually planned clearly, the day before. This close friend of mine, Ajeeth Kumar, who is also my colleague at Infosys, invited me for this short trip.I accepted. Meanwhile, a whatsapp group was created and discussions about the trip were going on.&lt;img src=&quot;https://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2015/06/resort.jpg?w=300&quot; alt=&quot;resort&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guys have decided to assemble at Kelambakkam bus stop at exactly at 9 am, the next day.  I started a bit late at 7.50 am from Guduvanchery and reached the spot around 9.15 am. It seems that the guys were really hungry and they were having a sound breakfast, at a hotel near Kelambakkam bus stop. I joined in between and had a tasty Poori with Aloo masala. We were 8 in numbers. Myself, Nivi - a body builder working in CTS, Yeshwa - a perfect event organizer who is also working in CTS, Sundar - a little bulk dude who has become an assistant professor, Ajeeth kumar - a colleague of mine at Infosys, Rajkumar - a serious dude who entertains us 24X7 with this jokes and who is actually going to Delhi next week to pursue his IAS coaching, Raghav - a friend of Rajkumar and a CTS employee and Sricharan - a old looking but super cool engineer. we had four bikes, few pulsars and a busty bullet ! After the breakfast, we traveled to the final spot, the Jade resort.This is my first trip to a resort. Jade resort is a budget one, with limited facilities, such as few indoor games and outdoor games, a swimming pool, a restaurant and a pitch for volley ball and a small beach. Its actually worth the money that we paid them.&lt;img src=&quot;https://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2015/06/group-pic.jpg?w=300&quot; alt=&quot;group pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we reached the resort, we decided to start the day by playing Cricket. Actually AjeethKumar was late. So he came directly to the resort in his scooty. Yes ! He rode a scooty all the way from Saidapet to the resort via Thiruvanmayur. So we played Cricket for around two hours making jokes about each other and commenting at each other’s game. No one scored a good runs. We were spending most of our time searching for the ball, that we hit accidentally outside of the ground. Ultimately one of the shot threw the ball so far and so long that we actually lost it. Then we paid a fine amount of Rs.50 for the lost ball. Yes! we got little tired and so we decided to chill at the swimming pool. We got back to the office and had few rounds of free juice that they provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we moved to the pool area. Actually the Swimming pool keeper didnt allow us, with the kind of trousers that we had. He asked us to enter the pool only in nylon trousers. So Sundar and Ajeeth went outside and bought us all , a pair of nylon trousers. Then we entered the pool. We spent almost two hours in the water chilling and playing some interesting games. One among them was, ‘Searching The Coin’. A person will throw a coin in to the pool, while other guys remain closing the eyes or facing in the opposite direction.And once he threw the coin, the guys will search for it and the person who picks it up first, is the winner ! And none of us knew proper swimming. So we all practiced and learnt a bit. Two hours left and we took some selfies too. It was a complete fun. So we all got little hungry. So we came out of the pool and dressed up deciding to have Lunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually we came out of the resort, to a good hotel, to have lunch. The lunch was good. We started with few Soups and dove directly into the main items. We bought few Rotis and Subjis and fried rices too. An hour passed, with the loud burps beeping, we decided to finish. We actually have eaten for Rs.2000. But yes, It was worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we drove back to the resort and decided to play few indoor games. We started with Table Tennis and Snooker. None of us have played snooker before. So, as usual we started advising each other and commenting each others moves, in the game. It was total fun. But boy! the real snooker is far difficult to play when compared to the computer game. Meanwhile two among us, were playing Table Tennis. Now is the most interesting part. Some random family including a pretty young woman, came in to the sports arena and joined us to play Table Tennis. It was fun. I meant both the game and staring at the beautiful girl. It went almost few hours and then we decided to hand over the sports items at the office and we went to the beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2015/06/beach.jpg?w=300&quot; alt=&quot;beach&quot; /&gt;It was a simple but a lovely private beach. It was like heaven especially when the rain started pouring. These guys actually decided not to get into the sea and stayed in the shore playing Catch&amp;amp;Catch with a tennis ball brought by one of my friends. I actually decided to head on the sea and chill. I walked alone towards the water and decided to get my feet dipped in it. But then the waves were brilliant and that changed my mind. I decided to dip myself in completely. Slowing it started raining heavier. I laid on the edge of the shore, looking at the sky and slowly feeling the chill waves tickling on my feet. It was heaven. Trust me ! the best time to enjoy a beach is during chill rain and an awesome weather. The sea stood magnificent. I got this superb feeling that this is turning to be the one of the best days of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slowly we dragged ourselves out of the beach as it was getting late and reached the office. We waited there for few minutes, for the rain to come down, so that we could start our journey return. But the rain didn’t seem to come down. So we started from there. I was sitting behind Nivi, in his Pulsar. None of us rode at high speed. Instead we were riding at normal speeds, enjoying the visuals at either sides of the road. The rain got heavier. But boy it was brilliant. This is the first time, I am actually riding in a bike, in ECR, during rain and especially during an awesome weather. It was heaven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached the Kelambakkam bus stand. We were little hungry and decided to have a tea &lt;img src=&quot;https://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2015/06/dsc_0046.jpg?w=300&quot; alt=&quot;DSC_0046&quot; /&gt;and a sandwich. We were discussing how the day was and had few laughs at our memories that we gathered during our college days, especially about the girls whom we had crush on. Then I decided to take a bus from Kelambakkam to my place. Those guys continued their bike rides to their respective places. I got a bus to my place and on the way back, I was listening to my favorite musician A.R.Rahman’s ‘Ok Kanmani’ album. The weather was good and the music multiplied the joy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started feeling so good. So pinged all those guys saying a big thanks for hosting the trip and for inviting me especially. I pinged them that this was one of the best days of my life and it was because of them. I promised them that I will write a blog post about this today and will share it with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is that post !
This post is actually dedicated to all those guys ! [ Nivi, Ajeeth, Sundhar, Yeshwanth, Raghav, RajKumar ]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much guys ! Love you loads ! :)
I simply can’t wait for the next trip to happen !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S -&amp;gt; I came home and talked to my dad. I told him that I had the best day of my life with the friends. He was happy. I told him that I should get a bike for me. I should roam around places and enjoy the world! He agreed and said “Yes ! pretty soon !”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to God too ! :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vigneshwar Venkatachalapathi</name></author><category term="Travel" /><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">Ever felt so happy and complete, after spending a beautiful day with wonderful friends and heading back home, listening to your favorite music? Yes! I had one of the best days of my life. Of course the title would give the best answer, to why my day was so special. It was a brilliant day which was actually planned clearly, the day before. This close friend of mine, Ajeeth Kumar, who is also my colleague at Infosys, invited me for this short trip.I accepted. Meanwhile, a whatsapp group was created and discussions about the trip were going on.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Stop The Goddamn Car !</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ideas/philosophy/stop-the-goddamn-car/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stop The Goddamn Car !" /><published>2015-06-17T11:05:10+05:30</published><updated>2015-06-17T11:05:10+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ideas/philosophy/stop-the-goddamn-car</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ideas/philosophy/stop-the-goddamn-car/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2015/06/cartoon-car-crash.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2015/06/cartoon-car-crash.jpg?w=300&quot; alt=&quot;Oh! Come On !&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Ever felt really bad after a stupid argument? over a stupid topic? with your close ones? Ever felt so exhausted after such bad moments and started to regret things? I also have encountered such moments. I recently got an important advice from my dad which was more like a solution to such kind of problems. So I thought I could share it with the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;He said ,&quot;The most important part of learning to drive a car, is knowing when to and how to stop the car&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I admired these words so much and tried to understand it better. An argument is carried through mood which is very dangerous.Because Mood in technical terms, is not a constant and is actually a variable. So it keeps on changing. So the way we react to situations and to the corresponding people, depends highly on the mood, that we possess at that point in time. So we should be very careful with our words and expressions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three kinds of people. One, who thinks 100% before taking a step. Two, who thinks,while taking a step. Three, who thinks, after taking a step. Of course the first kind are super intelligent. But most of us fall between the last two categories primarily because we can’t predict all such situations well ahead. But how can we pull ourselves out of the pit before falling deep? The car driving is a better example for such scenarios. There is a very thin margin between the moment you apply a break and the moment, an accident happens. The very act of arguing might lead to such situations too. Similar to the car driving scenario, there are two actors involved here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how to stop the car anyway?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily in the argument scenario, the margin is little bigger than that of the car scenario. The time you might get, to realize that an accident is about to happen is little larger. We would get a lot of clues that the argument, that we are having right now, might get a lot serious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I would like to call this point, in time as the &lt;strong&gt;Pinch point&lt;/strong&gt;. We can even take this literally. Right at this point we shall pinch ourselves and alert us that we should escape from this. The other clever options that we have is to ask for a &lt;strong&gt;Pause&lt;/strong&gt; ! a temporary stop in our argument and ask the target person some time before we can continue. Trust me the intensity will reduce for sure, the next time when u resume the argument. People will feel differently. The pace of it would have been reduced. The mood would have been changed. Time has the greatest power to change the mood. Give the argument, a break. And then resume it later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one simple way of avoiding such accidents in arguments, that I have learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S: I myself, is a beginner in following this new strategy. But I am sure, I would become good in due time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vigneshwar Venkatachalapathi</name></author><category term="Philosophy" /><category term="Ideas" /><category term="SelfImprovement" /><summary type="html">Ever felt really bad after a stupid argument? over a stupid topic? with your close ones? Ever felt so exhausted after such bad moments and started to regret things? I also have encountered such moments. I recently got an important advice from my dad which was more like a solution to such kind of problems. So I thought I could share it with the world.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Change within !</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ideas/philosophy/the-change-within/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Change within !" /><published>2015-04-25T16:55:10+05:30</published><updated>2015-04-25T16:55:10+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ideas/philosophy/the-change-within</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ideas/philosophy/the-change-within/">&lt;p&gt;“His character is so bad!”, “Such a nice person she is!”,”Hell knows, what a person he is! “.How many comments have we passed about other’s character?  How many times have we said “This is who I am!”,”That’s who she is!”?How many occasions, have we felt bad when somebody comments about our character or in general tries to describe about us to someone else? Well I am sure, I have done a lot of those mistakes and experienced a few from others.&lt;a href=&quot;https://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/character.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/character.jpg?w=300&quot; alt=&quot;Character&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am actually very afraid of books. I could clearly count the number of books that I have read so far. One is a Greek mythology based story and the other is a kid’s novel. But I had a different experience recently. Of course it’s my third book!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s &lt;strong&gt;‘Personality Development’ from Swami Vivekananda&lt;/strong&gt;. I started reading it because it’s got just 100 pages. In that book, there is one sentence that Swami Vivekananda exclaims about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;**Character is the repeated habits! And only repeated habits , alone can reform character**&quot;.

- **Swami Vivekananda **&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got so impressed at this quote! This is the only line that I remember from the entire book, now. I was thinking what he really meant, in this brilliant quote. Then I came up with a totally different perspective upon it. Let’s look at the statement once again for clarity. He has explained that character is actually the impressions that we create with our habits. So that means, &lt;strong&gt;there is a possibility for a change&lt;/strong&gt;! Of course the questions I have asked in the beginning of the post, is quite relevant to all of us. We are experiencing similar situations, in our day to day life. We are commenting about other’s character quite often. And we also have felt bad at different occasions, when somebody comments about us or to somebody else, which might be correct or sometimes not!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I sat down, thinking why do we comment about others character? Why does my team mate, say such things about me?Then after some time, I modified the question a bit, and thought how do people judge me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally realized that, my activities that I have demonstrated sometime and my behaviour that I express often made them think like that. Of course I am always interested in analyzing and improving me, because the &lt;strong&gt;opposite is not healthy and even virtually not possible&lt;/strong&gt;. So I concluded that the problem is partially on me too. Then I made my mind up and was further analyzing about my activities and the impressions that I create the positives and the negatives of them. In the end, I learned something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course the process of change is in progress for me. Wait! If this process is made in to a generic routine, everyone can use it! So I came up with below simple steps to change our character that Swami Vivekananda was exclaiming about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INTROSPECT YOURSELF&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;My father describes introspection like a scene and says “Bring the image of a court! You are the criminal and also the Judge. Now think in both the perspective and judge your action.” So analyse yourself and list down the opinions of others, which bother you.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;_&lt;Note&gt; Of course we can't consider every others opinion. List down, only from those that are close to you and from people who are precious to you._&lt;/Note&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;**FILTER **&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;From the list of opinions about your character, order them based on&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The reason for the opinion&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The possibility for a change.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE STUPID HABITS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This is the most important step. Write down the opinions on the left side .On the right side; write the list of your habits that cause those opinions.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FLIP THE BOARD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Try to flip the habits that cause those opinions, in a positive way.For instance:&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;_“Always angry”__- _Put a smile whenever you see them!&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Very silent”__-&lt;/em&gt; Go say Hi to the neighbour! Ask about the recent film that he has watched!&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;_“Jealous on someone”__- _call the same person and appreciate them!&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give it a try and you will be amazed, by how they see you there after! Trust me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no step 5! Because you are already a changed man!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt; &quot;But the most important point to remember here is, this is exactly how others feel too, when we comment about their character.&quot;  So let’s stop commenting on other's character because, it becomes out dated, when the target person has followed the steps.  Mind it!&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our character is what we make it! What we do! And it can be changed!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vigneshwar Venkatachalapathi</name></author><category term="Ideas" /><category term="SelfImprovement" /><summary type="html">“His character is so bad!”, “Such a nice person she is!”,”Hell knows, what a person he is! “.How many comments have we passed about other’s character?  How many times have we said “This is who I am!”,”That’s who she is!”?How many occasions, have we felt bad when somebody comments about our character or in general tries to describe about us to someone else? Well I am sure, I have done a lot of those mistakes and experienced a few from others.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Inspiration from within !</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ideas/philosophy/inspiration-from-within/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Inspiration from within !" /><published>2015-04-20T12:10:23+05:30</published><updated>2015-04-20T12:10:23+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ideas/philosophy/inspiration-from-within</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ideas/philosophy/inspiration-from-within/">&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, clearly no person other than Steve Jobs will be remembered by the world for what he did to technology and design. No other batsman other than Sachin Tendulkar is rightly portrayed to be the ‘God of Cricket’ for what he did to the game and for Indian cricket. No one other than Narayana Murthy will be appreciated in India as much for being a role model and perfect entrepreneur in the Indian IT industry. So we are easily inspired by all these success stories. Most of us will appreciate their work and efforts and move on. Some of us take a step further and try following the ideas and principles of these great achievers. Some of us build a huge wish list to achieve things, the way these individuals have done. I wanted to do that too. So I sat down to think about building a plan to accomplish it. All I could get were the various examples for great achievements like I mentioned above. So how should I come up with a practical protocol for this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After thinking for a while, I realized that those individuals who amazed me were also one among us at some point in time, but with a few differences – the passion for some specific thing and a desperate perseverance to achieve it. All I see is the image of all these people after reaching that point, after becoming successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are inspired by these people but how did they get inspiration before they had tasted success?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_383” align=”alignright” width=”300”]&lt;a href=&quot;https://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/power.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/power.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Inspiration from within !&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Inspiration from within ![/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally discovered that one factor that I have been missing! It’s ‘&lt;strong&gt;Inspiration from within&lt;/strong&gt;’. All those success stories will motivate us but the inspiration from within is responsible for making us work. The belief that we are going to get things done will make us work hard. We have to visualize ourselves being there, tasting success. The belief that there is something out there waiting for us is of high importance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do we get inspired from within?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only person who knows you the best,  is yourself. Inspiration from within comes in to making us perfect in the way we perform. We should find various aspects of ourselves that needs to be improved, that needs to be whitewashed and taken care of. If we keep improving ourselves in this way, with our prime aspiration in mind, we will be able to make it. In every step of our routine, we have to make sure that we are on the right path and ensuring that our effort and work for today are better than that of yesterday. The prime focus should be on changing ourselves without worrying about the surrounding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;The Nature has gifted us all with three eyes basically. Two among them are used to see the world around us. The third one is to see within us .Lets unlock the third eye! And get inspired !&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the practical protocol that I could come up in perceiving success. Let’s get in there! And get it done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s dive into ourselves, start exploring, believing and improving. Let’s get it started!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vigneshwar Venkatachalapathi</name></author><category term="Philosophy" /><category term="Ideas" /><category term="SelfImprovement" /><summary type="html">In my opinion, clearly no person other than Steve Jobs will be remembered by the world for what he did to technology and design. No other batsman other than Sachin Tendulkar is rightly portrayed to be the ‘God of Cricket’ for what he did to the game and for Indian cricket. No one other than Narayana Murthy will be appreciated in India as much for being a role model and perfect entrepreneur in the Indian IT industry. So we are easily inspired by all these success stories. Most of us will appreciate their work and efforts and move on. Some of us take a step further and try following the ideas and principles of these great achievers. Some of us build a huge wish list to achieve things, the way these individuals have done. I wanted to do that too. So I sat down to think about building a plan to accomplish it. All I could get were the various examples for great achievements like I mentioned above. So how should I come up with a practical protocol for this?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Music and Emotions !</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ideas/intellectual/music-and-emotions/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Music and Emotions !" /><published>2013-09-13T19:35:31+05:30</published><updated>2013-09-13T19:35:31+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ideas/intellectual/music-and-emotions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ideas/intellectual/music-and-emotions/">&lt;p&gt;We all love Music. Different genres. Different instruments . Different tunes. Everybody knows that. I am gonna talk about music in general. All I want to think about is ,  why music is so cool ?And why almost all people are really in love with it ? A simple answer might be , that listening to it makes one feel so good and that would be it for most of us. But we have to think a bit deep in here. If Music makes you feel so good, you should be enjoying almost any type of music. **But its not the case mostly. We wont like every song and composition. Our wish list is always limited. Why why why ? **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;( Chandler’s why ?..)  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its primarily because we wont always feel good on listening to every song. So my whole point here is , the Mood that we have at the moment i.e the type of feeling we experience currently determines the ability of us to like a particular tune mostly. But there are few exceptions when some people just listen to music just to experience its purity and the flow. Lets leave them. It doesn’t matter which age group you belong to! There is always a set of tunes that we cherish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/babylisteningwithheadphones4.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2013/09/babylisteningwithheadphones4.jpg?w=446&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Lets consider babies. Most of the times when a baby is disturbed and not feeling good, &lt;strong&gt;the Mom used to lay him on the cradle and swing it a bit singing a mild song&lt;/strong&gt;. I am not sure about the foreign habit equivalent to this. But this is mostly the case in India . And the baby feel relaxed and finally fall into sleep. The reason I think for this is because, Babies when  they are disturbed  they don’t feel good  and they obviously cant figure out anything. So when mom sings,  they are submerged into a strong soothing belief, that every thing is taken care of and they are protected .So finally they forget all their worries and fall in to deep sleep. So the tune that Mom sings doesn’t do the magic. Its the feeling the babies associate with it, does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets take Adults. we hear a hell lot of music. Mostly the powerful and energetic ones . We enjoy music a lot.  I have a lot of friends who listen to different kinds of music often. For instance some would always listen to rocking numbers that makes people dance in general , to make them feel good. Some would always listen to soft tunes which make them feel normal most of the times. Some people always listen to sad tunes that make them feel convinced for whatever the loss they had emotionally. I still remember that when I was in college , I personally used to listen to  so called &lt;strong&gt;Rising songs ! like the Dark knight rises theme by Hans , Thozha Munnal vaada song by Rahman etc &lt;/strong&gt; to make me feel ready before exams and presentations and seminars. They motivate me a lot.  **
**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Old people listen to spiritual songs and good old songs that convey most of good characters and morale ! M.S.V numbers do that magic. So the whole point here is Music and Emotions go hand in hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Music kindle our emotions. And it return our Emotions choose our music most of the times. So we have to understand that we use Music as a tool to support us morally  and thats how we like it. If  by any chance we could separate them and listen to music all alone , that would taste so good I hope ! And we would start liking a lot more  I guess ! We all should try it !&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Vigneshwar Venkatachalapathi</name></author><category term="Ideas" /><category term="Intellectual" /><summary type="html">We all love Music. Different genres. Different instruments . Different tunes. Everybody knows that. I am gonna talk about music in general. All I want to think about is ,  why music is so cool ?And why almost all people are really in love with it ? A simple answer might be , that listening to it makes one feel so good and that would be it for most of us. But we have to think a bit deep in here. If Music makes you feel so good, you should be enjoying almost any type of music. **But its not the case mostly. We wont like every song and composition. Our wish list is always limited. Why why why ? **</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why do most of the Movies suck these days ?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ideas/society/why-do-most-of-the-movies-suck-these-days/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why do most of the Movies suck these days ? " /><published>2013-08-01T08:36:57+05:30</published><updated>2013-08-01T08:36:57+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ideas/society/why-do-most-of-the-movies-suck-these-days</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ideas/society/why-do-most-of-the-movies-suck-these-days/">&lt;p&gt;Ya , We are in the age where Technology and Media have grown to a great extent  that Information travels so fast. People get information blindly in a matter of seconds of its occurrence via Social Media be it an original one or a fake message. So why is that relevant here ? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all watch Movies. Some do it regularly whenever a movie releases. Some watch them if it includes his or her favorite actors and actresses ! Some watch it for time pass. Some watch it seriously. Some watch it for comedy ! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know , most of movies suck nowadays ! All I am keen to know is , Do they seriously suck or its something else ? Lets go step by step !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;What are the most likely issues that make a movie suck so much ?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Movie specific issues –) &lt;/strong&gt;The Movie really sucks ! this includes reasons like (  Lame story , says something that cant be accepted , shows something that cant be watched etc)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People specific Issues –) &lt;/strong&gt; If your friends said that movie sucks , If your &lt;strong&gt;Facebook wall&lt;/strong&gt; is filled with posts that slams so bad about the movie, If  you &lt;strong&gt;pre- assume&lt;/strong&gt; that the movie will suck when it releases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I want to focus on is about the &lt;strong&gt;People Specific Issues ! &lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Since Most of the movies these days fail or suck so bad because of the second issue !  &lt;/strong&gt;Lets go back to good old days where a lot of stars ruled Cinema with their wonderful acting ! And the good old directors ruled people’s hearts with wonderful movies !  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”” align=”aligncenter” width=”249”]&lt;a href=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/sheep-group.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/sheep-group.jpg?w=249&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Don’t be one among them ! Have your own Original unique way ![/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you think most of the MGR and Sivaji  movies ran successfully all the time ? Well one might argue that ,Technology has not grown enough at that time, Competitions were minimum between the actors ! Well that is not true ! If you take any of those movies and play it now , It will contain a great story and its still watchable. But that is not my point in here. !  Why do most of the recent movies suck ? &lt;strong&gt;The better question to every man will be, Do the Movie really sucks or its just what you heard about it ?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I feel is that , a lot of recent movies are good !  It has got a great story line  and that the technology has grown so much , we are getting good context and clarity in movies ! Cinema has seriously developed.  Lets take a look at the steps that is usually followed by common man these days !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The trailer of the movie get released ! - We watch it , Fans get high ! Critics get high too in the opposite sense ! Common Man waits for the movie !&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The movie gets released ! Unfortunately everyone cant be able to watch it on first day ! So we should anyway watch in over the weekend or next ! But we wont wait . When we open our facebook account , our wall will be filled with random comments about the movie ! Most of them would be in negative sense !&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt; We gradually come to a conclusion that the movie sucks and slowly will delay our scheduled plan of watching the particular movie and finally dropping it !&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happens when almost all the people in state or even the country follows it ? ** The result is that Movie will anyway fails ! &lt;strong&gt;**&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my point here is ? &lt;strong&gt;Its not just the movies that suck ! Its we who talk much about it without watching , we argues a lot of what the movie has ,before actually watching it , its we who listens to others views about the movie and pre assume that its bad !&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I am trying to say in here  is not  against the &lt;strong&gt;Right to speak or Right to review &lt;/strong&gt; or something like that. What I am trying to say is &lt;strong&gt;Everyone has a unique taste ! &lt;/strong&gt;Some like Dosai ! Some like Idly ! Doesn’t mean both of them sucks !**&lt;br /&gt;
**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what &lt;strong&gt;I request you guys is ?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Please don't Listen to others views about the movie , before you actually watch it ! Have an Original Opinion ! Its You who are going to watch it ! Its what you like that matters ! Don't Pre assume stuff  about the movie and watch it then ! 
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; Before watching every movie , prepare yourself with the positive thought that the movie will be good ! and then watch it ! If its good , then remember it  and if its not just forget it and don't force your opinion to others !
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vigneshwar Venkatachalapathi</name></author><category term="Ideas" /><category term="Society" /><category term="Thoughts" /><summary type="html">Ya , We are in the age where Technology and Media have grown to a great extent  that Information travels so fast. People get information blindly in a matter of seconds of its occurrence via Social Media be it an original one or a fake message. So why is that relevant here ? </summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The so called RELATIONSHIPS !</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ideas/society/the-so-called-relationships-66/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The so called RELATIONSHIPS !" /><published>2012-04-27T16:42:36+05:30</published><updated>2012-04-27T16:42:36+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ideas/society/the-so-called-relationships-66</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ideas/society/the-so-called-relationships-66/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is relationship that simple to think?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”” align=”aligncenter” width=”281” caption=”                 wow!”]&lt;a href=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/4thgrade.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/4thgrade.jpg?w=487&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 4th std,some lovely cute classmate of us in nice orange frock seems to bother us more.Unfortunately she would be a top scorer.So we study just for competing with her.Later on at 8th grade our activities seem to change in favor of a lovely little lady in nice short chudi however our studies wont be the nice work to compete with.It goes and goes and there you go, at High school in the course of completing your school education,that lovely lady,beautiful looking ah you feel as if you could crush the entire mountain just for her.OH sadly u complete your school finally getting the flavor of higher education.Our family will be quite busy between march–july , and finally got a seat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We become  Freshmen to a famous college.We will find new friends,gain some confidence to talk with girls.And Believe me the first semester GPA we get would be the highest.Slowly it goes.Gang formation starts.All around fun going on.Sadly we will come across people buzzing the term &lt;strong&gt;GIRLFRIEND&lt;/strong&gt;/&lt;strong&gt;BOYFRIEND&lt;/strong&gt;. Friends consider the one with a gf/bf is gethu.And there we go finally got one.Mokka messages,DSLR magic,Facebook relationship statuses,lame outing rule us .We would lose control over our studies.And we spend time.It fakes us to be happy.Finally by the end of college life, we &lt;strong&gt;**beg for a placement in a company and got it. Unfortunately the partner might be interested in higher studies. **And he/she says “Sorry.I gotta go abroad.And we can just be friends.Sorry.Be in touch.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/lovers.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/lovers.jpg?w=487&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ahem our relationship is worth a great sorry ! ahem ! Little sad.Days pass.Finally in a company.Years pass.Party,Fashion,Money rule us.Here the term “BOYFRIEND/GIRLFRIEND” becomes practical and easy.We will party,waste money and health.He or she would bother you very less.We get attracted to many.But the sad fact is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;strong&gt;When it comes&lt;/strong&gt; to the talk on marriage and life, the word sorry sprouts.” Very Little Sadness.Years pass.Finally family comes in to focus.Mom stressing us to see photos.Matrimony,Family wealth,House rule us.Finally picked one.Lead it.Settled.**The thirst should at least stop there else **it becomes a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here we are&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where on earth is the true love?What does Relationship got to do with us?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We used to hear about fantasy stories and true love from olden days.It was there.Believe me this trend and western culture which we think as advanced and modern is forcing us to lead a stupid life.They reduce the grip that we possess on our life.We saw above how we tend to amuse things and assume them as love and finally dropping it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nowadays “relationships” come as a pair with “break-up”&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Grandparents,parents all had true love.Its not because they are old.Its because they had patience.Its not that arranged family supported marriages lead to true love.Even history has beautiful love stories.They remained not just stories but as an incidents of remembrance for us.They taught us how love has to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be in your breadth.You should even give your life to get her.She should be the one who balances all your activities,one who understand you,one who thinks always about you,one who believes that u are her everything and finally one who lives for you.The only breakup is your death in the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly this remains a piece of imagination in these days.So&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to all who are in &lt;strong&gt;so called relationship&lt;/strong&gt; –&amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;THINK&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to all who are single–&amp;gt;”&lt;strong&gt;Your safe.Lets wait”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/true-love2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/true-love2.jpg?w=487&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vigneshwar Venkatachalapathi</name></author><category term="Ideas" /><category term="Society" /><category term="Intellectual" /><summary type="html">Is relationship that simple to think?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nowhere to Nowhere!! but still expectations!!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ideas/philosophy/nowhere-to-nowhere-but-still-expectations/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nowhere to Nowhere!! but still expectations!! " /><published>2011-07-14T20:20:14+05:30</published><updated>2011-07-14T20:20:14+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ideas/philosophy/nowhere-to-nowhere-but-still-expectations</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ideas/philosophy/nowhere-to-nowhere-but-still-expectations/">&lt;p&gt;Its  starts  from nowhere! where a soul gets life and a life gets a body and the body wastes some space!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever wondered ,where we come from?where we are heading to?what we need?and why? for all these.. how a baby is destined to be born to particular couple? who plans this entire process ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_32” align=”aligncenter” width=”300” caption=”NOWHERE”]&lt;a href=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/nowhere-12212.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/nowhere-12212.jpg?w=300&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my view, Life is nothing but a temporary stay in a well equipped gigantic hotel room (“The Earth”).we never realize the ultra thin span of this life because of the temporary pleasures and acquaintances.I was wondering what made that super power to direct me to this world ? Am I bound to enjoy the stay or do something that stands for a help ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best and the cutest period of this stay is “&lt;strong&gt;BABY’S TIME”.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;why all people love babies and why they are considered cute! lets think about it for a minute! &lt;strong&gt;ITS STARTS WITH A LOUD CRY! exclaiming to the world “I am one among you idiots”.And what makes them special is that “the never expect anything! all they need is just a milk bottle and full of happiness “.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They never expect &lt;strong&gt;respect&lt;/strong&gt;!they never expect &lt;strong&gt;response&lt;/strong&gt; ! and when something was missing , they starts crying . About thoughts ,usually they don’t waste them. But the most surprising thing is their learning ability! Imagine a situation where you are in the middle of an empty space full of white, and u got no memory, no words ,no knowledge,nothing !! And you are about to start realize and think!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is the case with  a new born baby.&lt;strong&gt;THEY ARE THE BEST STUDENTS.THEY LEARN BY PRACTICE,BY SIGHT,BY HEARING,BY FEELING EVERYTHING NEW!!. And the sense of clarity of not expecting anything makes them CUTE!! &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_27” align=”alignleft” width=”210” caption=”clarity and emptiness!!    ”]&lt;a href=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/cute-baby.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/cute-baby.jpg?w=300&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THE QUESTION IS,WHY BABIES ARE CONSIDERED CUTE AND LOVED BY ALL ,WHILE ADULTS LIKE US ARE NOT TREATED SO???&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason behind that is simple ! EXPECTATIONS..we start expecting respect from others! response from others!! and care much about what others think about us!! While the babies never do this..and thats wat make them special..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it so continues to grow, to learn , to even expect like common Adult! joining the selfish community where it belongs to…Now we are grownups ! and here it starts - the development of selfish identity!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;we step into the new era of so called tradition and fashion all over! we score acquaintances! we start thinking that its my life and Iam the one to take care of it! **SLOWLY THE ACQUAINTANCES GLOW MORE THAN THE TRUE RELATIONSHIPS AND LOVE ! CRUSHES BRUSH PEOPLE!! we start moving away from our parents. Its the period where we are bound to believe that these acquaintances to be true! and that’s where the problem starts! ** and it continues ,finally in search of the right one!! got it!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_29” align=”aligncenter” width=”112” caption=”stylish man”]&lt;a href=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/stylish-man1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/stylish-man1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it contines, goes on and on! a self sustained group called family develops! new new cries and new new yells !! and chain extends and the &lt;strong&gt;realization phase&lt;/strong&gt; begins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this we start realizing the truth! the reality when it happens to our juniors! we realize the impact of expectations as it will be hurt! we realize that we were wrong ! The truth begins! The search begins! . we become old! we feel that we are not so important to this hotel ! we start expressing ! we realize that no one hear us! and we become useless dappa!! so called grandpa !!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[caption id=”attachment_30” align=”aligncenter” width=”300” caption=”                              realization phase                                                            ”]&lt;a href=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/grandpachair.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/grandpachair.gif?w=300&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;     [/caption]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;and there you go!..towards nowhere once again! My dad used to talk about the “learning curve” that I definitely need to stress about!!! &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The learning curve is as follows!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/learning-curve.gif&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2011/07/learning-curve.gif?w=300&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The learning curve denotes the ability of life to observe things at different stages! The baby starts learning  and it grows–&amp;gt;  the credit reaches the peak at 20 and starts declining so well &lt;strong&gt; AND THE DECAY OF INFORMATION REGARDING REALITY BEGINS..AND THIS IS THE REASON WHY OUR GRANDPARENTS USED TO YELL  ADVICES ,WHICH NO ONE CARE!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AND IN THE END!! WHO ARE YOU? WHAT U HAVE DONE? DO I KNOW YOU?  and these are just that remain!! &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;**&lt;/em&gt;so my point is ,ITS CLEAR THAT WE ARE GOING TO TAKE NOTHING WITH US IN THE END!! THEN WHY IS SUCH A CRAZE OVER MONEY AND UNSTABLE PLEASURES? LETS HELP THE NEEDY !!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vigneshwar Venkatachalapathi</name></author><category term="Ideas" /><category term="Intellectual" /><category term="Philosophy" /><summary type="html">Its  starts  from nowhere! where a soul gets life and a life gets a body and the body wastes some space!!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Information Technology - is not just what you think !!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ideas/unique/itdefinition/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Information Technology - is not just what you think !!" /><published>2011-02-04T20:11:16+05:30</published><updated>2011-02-04T20:11:16+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ideas/unique/itdefinition</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ideas/unique/itdefinition/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/it.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/it.jpg?w=300&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oxford&lt;/strong&gt; says   “the study or use of systems (especially computers and telecommunications) for storing, retrieving, and sending information”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Websters&lt;/strong&gt; says   “the study, design, development, implementation, support or management of computer-based information systems, particularly software applications and computer hardware.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you think Information technology is just this???????&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just cant believe IT treated just for computing and telecommunications. Here is my view of What IT is all about ?Do follow me to go behind BC’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my view IT is the backbone of almost all processes existing in the universe.UNIVERSE is made up of millions of interconnected- processes. Each process is associated with** 3 P’s** .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/new-picture-2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/new-picture-2.jpg?w=300&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;PURPOSE specifies what the process is intended to do.PRIORITY describes the order of execution of various sub resources involved in the process and PATTERN OF OPERATIONS specifies in what order the various sub resources should be executed to achieve the desired purpose.The following example best suits this IDEA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets take this simple example&lt;a href=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/picture-7.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/picture-7.png?w=300&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above is a simple picture demonstrating a simple process “ glowing of a bulb when switched ON”.Lets go somewhat deep in to it. The purpose of this process is to glow light ultimately.The available various resources are “Bulb,switch,connecting wires and electricity (i.e electrons)”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PATTERN OF OPERATIONS :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The switch should be triggered ON.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Next the electrons should start flowing through the wires&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The flowing electrons should heat the metal in bulb and hence the bulb glows.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SO THE PRIORITY IS AS FOLLOWS :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Switch.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Motion of electrons.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;bulb being triggered.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_why cant we have like this? Think ..Let the bulb glows first -&amp;gt; then the electrons pass through wires -&amp;gt; and then the switch may be triggered ON. Or in any order , you like _?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SO WHAT MY IDEA SAY IS THAT , the purpose  and the priorities of available resources comes under “INFORMATION”,and the pattern of operations under “TECHNOLOGY”. So here in this example .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LIGHT GLOWING PROCESS - the INFORMATION are “ purpose  - to give light, and the priorities of the available resources such as ‘switch(1),Motion of electrons(2),Bulb being triggered(3)’ “ and the TECHNOLOGY is when electrons are accelerated the collide among them and produce large scale energy which heats filament and hence light “&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a process to happen the available resources should be prioritized and should be regulated in the destined order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets take another example.In Olden days the kings used to send their sweet love messages to their “QUEENS” :-P (note that its plural :-P) . OK ..They use DOVES to send their messages.lets analyze this simple process .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/the-young-victoria-1acd57.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/the-young-victoria-1acd57.jpg?w=136&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/the-young-victoria-1acd57.jpg&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/dove.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/dove.jpg?w=120&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/kingjohniii_22486.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/kingjohniii_22486.jpg?w=143&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this process, the purpose is the king wants to communicate his intention to queen,and the available resources are dove,information,paper, and the pattern of operations are&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;sketch data in the paper&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;hung it in birds legs&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;direct the bird in right direction and send it&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus for this process to happen every step as mentioned above should happen in the destined order.So in this example the INFORMATION  includes “ the purpose - communicating his intention to queen, and priority of the available resources such as  Pen down info(1),hung it on birds legs(2),train it in right direction and send(3) “ and the Technology used is “ Dove can carry a piece of paper  from one place to another” .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even this is same going on in natural processes too.&lt;a href=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/plant_growth.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/photosynthesis-color.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/photosynthesis-color.jpg?w=300&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Lets take this photosynthesis  process as example .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;INFORMATION&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;purpose : to grow ,bear fruits  and flowers,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;priorities : as u see in the above diagram&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;absorb solar energy&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;convert water and light to food&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;transfer to other parts&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TECHNOLOGY&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;carbondioxide +water + co2  = food for plants&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So any process is associated with Information and technology. So we can say IT is the backbone of all processes.BUT there is another major fact to be considered “TIME”.So any process happens between “START” and “STOP”.&lt;strong&gt;So  thinking what separates start and stop?&lt;/strong&gt; I got the answer “TIME” .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Its the time that separates start and stop, between which a process happens behind which INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY lies. &lt;strong&gt;IMAGINE AN UNIVERSE  WITH NO TIME???&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is” &lt;strong&gt;NOTHING&lt;/strong&gt;”. SO for each and every process to happen , time paves the path , IT defines them.Hence if we see in this view, then&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“TIME IS THE KING OF UNIVERSE AND INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY IS THE SUCCESSOR OF TIME “&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; ….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SO TO MY VIEW, Information technology is not just what we say.Its something far apart. IT’s origin can be described as the start of universe,the beginning of processes.But man has redefined the identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THIS IS OUR TRUE IDENTITY PEOPLE!&lt;/strong&gt;!!! Information technology  is not just computer and stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this is my definition of information technology.view it in this perpective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PROUD TO BE AN ‘IT’ -IAN&lt;/strong&gt;!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“TIME AND WORDS ONCE SPENT CAN NEVER BE RETRIVED”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;my dad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I dedicate my view to my dad who taught me the entire world.Hats of to you dad. :) :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vigneshwar Venkatachalapathi</name></author><category term="Ideas" /><category term="Unique" /><summary type="html">Oxford says   “the study or use of systems (especially computers and telecommunications) for storing, retrieving, and sending information”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Assumptions</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ideas/society/assumptions/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Assumptions" /><published>2011-02-01T16:54:20+05:30</published><updated>2011-02-01T16:54:20+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ideas/society/assumptions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ideas/society/assumptions/">&lt;p&gt;Do you really think &lt;strong&gt;a synonym is actually a synonym&lt;/strong&gt;?.. Oops even now…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To My View, there is nothing called a synonym.Lets take this example .Whats this ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/apple-61.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/apple-61.jpg?w=148&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Realize this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We usually call this as an apple.Ok! who taught you that this is an apple?or lets take this. we were taught when we we’re in KG’s, and we are asked to follow that. when you ask the same question to your teacher or elders in general , they might have the same answer. Lets think about the orgin of languages or even communication for instance !we never realize why we are asked to call this NewtonTool as an apple ? Its the artificially created logic of the world that “ mandatory should always be mandatory”.when Adam was very hungry he might have shouted at Eve “guuuiiiivvv meeyeeeee aaaaaapppllllaaaaaa” as he was interested in this beautiful eatable, who Knows ??? Later on , It would be called as apple…a synonym for a word or a reference for a thing is assumed when it is followed by many.So its not a big thing even one masters Oxfords advanced english dictionary, since he had grazed on a virtual land.funny rite?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so its an assumption that created the synonym,the reference for understanding.To all those who seek uniqueness- you are still following the beaten track ! However science is not like that.science has proof though it involves assumptions and predictions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So people who are less effective in language vocabulary should not be discouraged , since they are at least trying to unique . So what about you ?huh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just an idea or a simple view..Please think over it :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vigneshwar Venkatachalapathi</name></author><category term="Ideas" /><category term="Society" /><category term="Intellectual" /><summary type="html">Do you really think a synonym is actually a synonym?.. Oops even now…</summary></entry></feed>
