<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-02-04T22:23:23+08:00</updated><id>https://themoralpanda.github.io//</id><title type="html">Vig Venkat</title><subtitle>Personal site of Vigneshwar Venkatachalapathi. Software Engineer, Blogger, Problem Solver, Creationist.</subtitle><author><name>Vig Venkat</name><email>haivicky@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Here is why I am losing interests on my country and I dont need help</title><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/opinion/society/Here-is-why-I-am-losing-interests-in-my-country-and-I-don't-need-help!/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Here is why I am losing interests on my country and I dont need help" /><published>2017-06-13T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-06-13T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://themoralpanda.github.io/opinion/society/Here%20is%20why%20I%20am%20losing%20interests%20in%20my%20country%20and%20I%20don't%20need%20help!</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://themoralpanda.github.io/opinion/society/Here-is-why-I-am-losing-interests-in-my-country-and-I-don't-need-help!/">&lt;p&gt;I am an Indian. A 24 year old. Spent all my 24 years so far in India except few vacations. Right through my school days, I was taught Patriotism via books, Prayers, Sports routines and early celebrations of historically important days. During those days, I felt it. The pride, the energy and the importance. But as I grew up and became an adult and especially after the arrival of the social media, I am slowly feeling the reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not loosing interests because of Government. Because, they are doing what they have been doing and they will be doing the same. So Never mind!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its not because of the Celebrities either. They are also doing the same thing that they have been doing all the time. Pretending to be a beacon at the sea shore but flickering like a useless street lamp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am annoyed because of the People. I am loosing patriotism because of the my brothers and sisters out there. The People. Here is why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People ask for “No Reservation!”. But they don’t fight for “No Castes”. Because No Reservation means all people are equal. Then why not fight for “No Caste” as a whole. If people are so proud of who they are and what caste they belong to, how can they ask for “No Reservation”, which ultimately says, that all people are equal.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One religion accuses other religion of spreading their religion. But they themselves post, “In order to have a beautiful life, say the mantras of this God”, in almost all the MTC buses.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And the children are becoming desperate when it comes to Love. And the parents are becoming desperate when it comes to Marriage.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Epic pilgrimages underwent. Infinite discourses about God, has been spread. Truck load of comments about the society. Yet, people don’t stop commenting about others values.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The same actor, who talks great about, women and respect towards them, dances for an item song, in every fucking movie.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One week before, they accuse him of knowing nothing about politics and condemns him from entering in to politics, and exactly one week later, call him “Thalaivaaaa” posting a picture from his upcoming movie.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some build apartments in every little lakes. Many buy a comfortable home in the same apartment. And all complain about water scarcity and Government’s measures on it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They say, discrimination of any form, is an offense. But all discrimination of all kinds, happens inside the homes. They can’t even stand up against their own parent’s societal values.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A single person drives a Sedan alone, daily to office, and complains about Pollution in the city.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;They worry so much about U.S coming out of Paris climate change treaty, but continue cutting trees and conquer lakes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A cow is an holy animal whereas a chicken is a Satan’s curse.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If animals know about the purspose of dustbins, then I bet that they would not throw away anything on the roads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lists goes on and on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real change that is required in India, is the change in people’s mind.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vig Venkat</name><email>haivicky@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Opinions" /><category term="Society" /><category term="Musing" /><summary type="html">I am an Indian. A 24 year old. Spent all my 24 years so far in India except few vacations. Right through my school days, I was taught Patriotism via books, Prayers, Sports routines and early celebrations of historically important days. During those days, I felt it. The pride, the energy and the importance. But as I grew up and became an adult and especially after the arrival of the social media, I am slowly feeling the reality.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A 24 year old’s struggle to learn Music</title><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/personal/experience/A-24yr-old's-struggle-to-learn-Music/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A 24 year old's struggle to learn Music" /><published>2017-04-22T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2017-04-22T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://themoralpanda.github.io/personal/experience/A%2024yr%20old's%20struggle%20to%20learn%20Music</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://themoralpanda.github.io/personal/experience/A-24yr-old's-struggle-to-learn-Music/">&lt;p&gt;Firstly listen to the below wonderful piece composed by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ludovicoeinaudi.com/&quot; title=&quot;Ludovico Einaudi&quot;&gt;Ludovico Einaudi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Courtesy of embedresponsively.com //--&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;responsive-video-container&quot;&gt;

  &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/X1DRDcGlSsE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you notice the talent? The involvement? The fingers moving effortlessly with absolute passion for the tune? The background orchestra supporting like pillars of a beautiful monument? The violins and cellos. This is a thing of a beauty. Now this is one beautiful example of a sincere and a passionate work. Isn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;I have a huge respect and admiration for artists and musicians. Because their work involves another dimension. A normal human being is engulfed in the worlds monotony and materialism and to his unluck and reality, he is involved in quest for money especially to support his family and himself. It is not his mistake. Not everybody is lucky to have an environment that supports following his or her passion. &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a 24 year old aspiring Keyboard student. The truth is, my family has a no background on Music or arts. My ancestors were mostly survivors. And to the almighty’s grace and my parents hardwork, I am in this position to atleast start learning now and to appreciate other things. My school days were comfortable but not too much. My parents struggled so much to put all the three of us in school and then into college, and they could not afford to think of anything beyond that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first came in touch with this Music and Keyboard in 8th grade, in Dr.RKV school, back in my native Sattur. That year, the school appointed a Music teacher, who came to the school twice in a week to teach some interested students, to play music. I was interested suddenly. I volunteered in my Extracurricular class and reached out to him. There was only one Keyboard in the school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He taught me, what is an Octave? He gave me the initial drawing with the letters. &lt;strong&gt;CDEFGABC&lt;/strong&gt;. After few weeks, he gave me the notes of the song &lt;strong&gt;“Suttum Vizhi Sudarae”__&lt;/strong&gt; from the movie &lt;strong&gt;“Ghajini”&lt;/strong&gt;, which was a huge hit song at that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile owing to my interest, My dad instantly ordered a Keyboard worth Rs.13000 and gifted me. He used to tell my mom, that “Playing music helps relax the mind and elevates one”. He has got a wonderful intellect and wisdom that is highly unique among parents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I practised the notes for that song in the new keyboard and played it in front of my school, during the Annual day function at my school. Everyone appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There you go. I performed my first ever concert, right in the beginning of my learning. Even though its only one simple song. But heck yeah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that I was put in to the hostel and thats all. And things also changed at school. My music learning and interest started to diminish. I moved to another residential school for the higher secondary in another town, where the prime focus is on Board examinations. The keyboard was left in my native town, on top of the cupboard left for the rats to eat the thermocoal cups and the paper boxes, that surrounded my keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then I came to college in chennai. The four years was absolutely wasted doing useless things. I almost forgot about music and keyboard. My keyboard was still in my native place. One day in my final year of college, suddenly it struck me. I was thinking about my keyboard and my music journey. I went in search of a Leather bag for keyboard and bought it in the city. And when I went back to my native, I was very lucky to find that my Keyboard was in good condition. Only the outer boxes have been terribly damaged by rats. The keyboard was little dirty but worked perfectly. And thanks to the rats coz they left the charger and its wire without eating. &lt;strong&gt;A hugh sigh of relief&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After two years, I joined a Keyboard class near my workplace. He taught me some basic keyboard music using Tamil classical raagams. He gave me notes in tamil. I learned it for 3 months. But then, I decided I have to change to western. Because working in IT sector, I might have to travel to different places at different point in time. So if I learn in Tamil notes, I might not be able to continue in other states or in other countries. So I joined another place. Its VJ school of Music in Chennai. They teach you western music. And its been 8 months since I have joined there. They teach you with a TRINITY international syllabus. And so far I am learning a lot. Its really good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its funny and pleasing to note, that most of the students who come to that school are below 10 years old. I even met a 4 year old who joined the keyboard class. The tutors used to continously ask him to press a button. The boy ends up smiling and looking around and rarely touchin the keyboard. But the most intersting part to note here is, the parents of those young kids are waiting outside of the classroom, looking through the glass walls, watching their children play something. And those kids even take some homework, which have be to completed before the next class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my close &lt;del&gt;friends&lt;/del&gt; is a Bharathanatyam dancer. She is a professional now. She has been training since she was a six year old. She used to often say me, how her mother used to push her to classes and force her to commit to learning the art. How much she was supporting her to perceive dance as a passion. I have watched my friend perform in a live show. I used to sit in awe with the colors and the lights and how my friend and her team performs. I always had a huge respect for artists. So she was an inspiration in that aspect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;And looking at these young children and their parents, I used to think, if my parents and relatives had any intersts or background, they would have motivated me right from my childhood. And I would be a true professional now, like my dancer friend. I would be doing professional shows and people would admire my work and I would be creating lovely pieces of music by now. &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But nevermind! People say, ** It’s never too late **. Its never too late to start some thing good. Its never too late to be grateful and persue some passionate work. I am pretty sure, I would become successful in future with my music. &lt;strong&gt;Because, I understand that I have deep soul driven intution and passion for music. And I have a huge respect for art and creativity.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes. My parents were not like those parents with music and art awareness. But they taught me some sincere dedication and kindness in persuing things. My mother taught me what is dedication, with her bhakthi and devotion to God. My father taught me wisdom and Gratitude which led to this current thought&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt; Its never too late&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I might be a beginner in playing music. But I am an expert in listening and appreciating Music. Because I believe in this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;__If you want to learn some art, the first step as a grown up, is to have respect towards arts and artists and then to commit and dedicate ourselves to it __&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My music education is going in parallel. But that doesn’t stop me from creating music. &lt;strong&gt;The below is a piece of Electron Dance MIX that I created recently&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- Courtesy of embedresponsively.com //--&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;responsive-video-container&quot;&gt;

  &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Uf04dfaq9EU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S I also have some struggle in commiting as a grown up. So I will discuss on how I am overcame that in my next blog. Whatever happens, I am not gonna stop :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vig Venkat</name><email>haivicky@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Experience" /><category term="Motivation" /><category term="Introspection" /><summary type="html">Firstly listen to the below wonderful piece composed by Ludovico Einaudi</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Stop The Goddamn Car !</title><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/stop-the-goddamn-car/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stop The Goddamn Car !" /><published>2015-06-17T13:35:10+08:00</published><updated>2015-06-17T13:35:10+08:00</updated><id>https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/stop-the-goddamn-car</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/stop-the-goddamn-car/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2015/06/cartoon-car-crash.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2015/06/cartoon-car-crash.jpg?w=300&quot; alt=&quot;Oh! Come On !&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Ever felt really bad after a stupid argument? over a stupid topic? with your close ones? Ever felt so exhausted after such bad moments and started to regret things? I also have encountered such moments. I recently got an important advice from my dad which was more like a solution to such kind of problems. So I thought I could share it with the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;He said ,&quot;The most important part of learning to drive a car, is knowing when to and how to stop the car&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I admired these words so much and tried to understand it better. An argument is carried through mood which is very dangerous.Because Mood in technical terms, is not a constant and is actually a variable. So it keeps on changing. So the way we react to situations and to the corresponding people, depends highly on the mood, that we possess at that point in time. So we should be very careful with our words and expressions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three kinds of people. One, who thinks 100% before taking a step. Two, who thinks,while taking a step. Three, who thinks, after taking a step. Of course the first kind are super intelligent. But most of us fall between the last two categories primarily because we can’t predict all such situations well ahead. But how can we pull ourselves out of the pit before falling deep? The car driving is a better example for such scenarios. There is a very thin margin between the moment you apply a break and the moment, an accident happens. The very act of arguing might lead to such situations too. Similar to the car driving scenario, there are two actors involved here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how to stop the car anyway?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily in the argument scenario, the margin is little bigger than that of the car scenario. The time you might get, to realize that an accident is about to happen is little larger. We would get a lot of clues that the argument, that we are having right now, might get a lot serious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I would like to call this point, in time as the &lt;strong&gt;Pinch point&lt;/strong&gt;. We can even take this literally. Right at this point we shall pinch ourselves and alert us that we should escape from this. The other clever options that we have is to ask for a &lt;strong&gt;Pause&lt;/strong&gt; ! a temporary stop in our argument and ask the target person some time before we can continue. Trust me the intensity will reduce for sure, the next time when u resume the argument. People will feel differently. The pace of it would have been reduced. The mood would have been changed. Time has the greatest power to change the mood. Give the argument, a break. And then resume it later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one simple way of avoiding such accidents in arguments, that I have learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S: I myself, is a beginner in following this new strategy. But I am sure, I would become good in due time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vig Venkat</name><email>haivicky@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Philosophy" /><category term="Ideas" /><category term="SelfImprovement" /><summary type="html">Ever felt really bad after a stupid argument? over a stupid topic? with your close ones? Ever felt so exhausted after such bad moments and started to regret things? I also have encountered such moments. I recently got an important advice from my dad which was more like a solution to such kind of problems. So I thought I could share it with the world.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Inspiration from within !</title><link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/inspiration-from-within/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Inspiration from within !" /><published>2015-04-20T14:40:23+08:00</published><updated>2015-04-20T14:40:23+08:00</updated><id>https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/inspiration-from-within</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://themoralpanda.github.io/ideas/philosophy/inspiration-from-within/">&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, clearly no person other than Steve Jobs will be remembered by the world for what he did to technology and design. No other batsman other than Sachin Tendulkar is rightly portrayed to be the ‘God of Cricket’ for what he did to the game and for Indian cricket. No one other than Narayana Murthy will be appreciated in India as much for being a role model and perfect entrepreneur in the Indian IT industry. So we are easily inspired by all these success stories. Most of us will appreciate their work and efforts and move on. Some of us take a step further and try following the ideas and principles of these great achievers. Some of us build a huge wish list to achieve things, the way these individuals have done. I wanted to do that too. So I sat down to think about building a plan to accomplish it. All I could get were the various examples for great achievements like I mentioned above. So how should I come up with a practical protocol for this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After thinking for a while, I realized that those individuals who amazed me were also one among us at some point in time, but with a few differences – the passion for some specific thing and a desperate perseverance to achieve it. All I see is the image of all these people after reaching that point, after becoming successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are inspired by these people but how did they get inspiration before they had tasted success?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/power.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://vickyexplored.files.wordpress.com/2015/04/power.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Inspiration from within !&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Inspiration from within !&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally discovered that one factor that I have been missing! It’s ‘&lt;strong&gt;Inspiration from within&lt;/strong&gt;’. All those success stories will motivate us but the inspiration from within is responsible for making us work. The belief that we are going to get things done will make us work hard. We have to visualize ourselves being there, tasting success. The belief that there is something out there waiting for us is of high importance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do we get inspired from within?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only person who knows you the best,  is yourself. Inspiration from within comes in to making us perfect in the way we perform. We should find various aspects of ourselves that needs to be improved, that needs to be whitewashed and taken care of. If we keep improving ourselves in this way, with our prime aspiration in mind, we will be able to make it. In every step of our routine, we have to make sure that we are on the right path and ensuring that our effort and work for today are better than that of yesterday. The prime focus should be on changing ourselves without worrying about the surrounding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;The Nature has gifted us all with three eyes basically. Two among them are used to see the world around us. The third one is to see within us .Lets unlock the third eye! And get inspired !&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the practical protocol that I could come up in perceiving success. Let’s get in there! And get it done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s dive into ourselves, start exploring, believing and improving. Let’s get it started!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Vig Venkat</name><email>haivicky@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Philosophy" /><category term="Ideas" /><category term="SelfImprovement" /><summary type="html">In my opinion, clearly no person other than Steve Jobs will be remembered by the world for what he did to technology and design. No other batsman other than Sachin Tendulkar is rightly portrayed to be the ‘God of Cricket’ for what he did to the game and for Indian cricket. No one other than Narayana Murthy will be appreciated in India as much for being a role model and perfect entrepreneur in the Indian IT industry. So we are easily inspired by all these success stories. Most of us will appreciate their work and efforts and move on. Some of us take a step further and try following the ideas and principles of these great achievers. Some of us build a huge wish list to achieve things, the way these individuals have done. I wanted to do that too. So I sat down to think about building a plan to accomplish it. All I could get were the various examples for great achievements like I mentioned above. So how should I come up with a practical protocol for this?</summary></entry></feed>
