<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Vig Venkat</title>
    <link>https://themoralpanda.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Vig Venkat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://themoralpanda.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Flaunting With Ease</title>
      <link>https://themoralpanda.github.io/blog/2024-11-09-flaunting-with-ease/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://themoralpanda.github.io/blog/2024-11-09-flaunting-with-ease/</guid>
      <description>why are you not grounded? why is there a tinge of high,
and nervousness?
did you dress up for the party?
or did you just want to express ur uniqueness?
that you are unique and different from peers.
different from your class mates.
different from your college mates.
different among your work mates.
why?
the word flaunting struck you.
why?
may be you are really flaunting?
the excitement before the party, you assumed it was</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Belly, my best friend</title>
      <link>https://themoralpanda.github.io/blog/belly-my-best-friend/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://themoralpanda.github.io/blog/belly-my-best-friend/</guid>
      <description>In the past few years, I paid a very close attention to my stomach and things I ate. Here are the points I discovered that was very helpful to myself.
The less, the size of the meal I have, the more I feel alert and at ease after eating.
Eating two course meal everyday elevates my concentration at work. Especially having a brunch in the morning at around 11AM and dinner around 7PM, with a 3:30 to 4pm small snack break.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A 24 year old&#39;s struggle to learn Music</title>
      <link>https://themoralpanda.github.io/blog/2017-04-22-a-24yr-olds-struggle-to-learn-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://themoralpanda.github.io/blog/2017-04-22-a-24yr-olds-struggle-to-learn-music/</guid>
      <description>Firstly listen to the below wonderful piece composed by Ludovico Einaudi
Did you notice the talent? The involvement? The fingers moving effortlessly with absolute passion for the tune? The background orchestra supporting like pillars of a beautiful monument? The violins and cellos. This is a thing of a beauty. Now this is one beautiful example of a sincere and a passionate work. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it?
I have a huge respect and admiration for artists and musicians.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop The Goddamn Car !</title>
      <link>https://themoralpanda.github.io/blog/2015-06-17-stop-the-goddamn-car/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 05:35:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://themoralpanda.github.io/blog/2015-06-17-stop-the-goddamn-car/</guid>
      <description>Ever felt really bad after a stupid argument? over a stupid topic? with your close ones? Ever felt so exhausted after such bad moments and started to regret things? I also have encountered such moments. I recently got an important advice from my dad which was more like a solution to such kind of problems. So I thought I could share it with the world.
He said ,&#34;The most important part of learning to drive a car, is knowing when to and how to stop the car&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inspiration from within !</title>
      <link>https://themoralpanda.github.io/blog/2015-04-20-inspiration-from-within/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 06:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://themoralpanda.github.io/blog/2015-04-20-inspiration-from-within/</guid>
      <description>In my opinion, clearly no person other than Steve Jobs will be remembered by the world for what he did to technology and design. No other batsman other than Sachin Tendulkar is rightly portrayed to be the &amp;lsquo;God of Cricket&amp;rsquo; for what he did to the game and for Indian cricket. No one other than Narayana Murthy will be appreciated in India as much for being a role model and perfect entrepreneur in the Indian IT industry.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
