<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vig Venkat</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vig Venkat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Belly, my best friend</title>
      <link>/blog/belly-my-best-friend/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/belly-my-best-friend/</guid>
      <description>In the past few years, I paid a very close attention to my stomach and things I ate. Here are the points I discovered that was very helpful to myself.
  The less, the size of the meal I have, the more I feel alert and at ease after eating.
  Eating two course meal everyday elevates my concentration at work. Especially having a brunch in the morning at around 11AM and dinner around 7PM, with a 3:30 to 4pm small snack break.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music productions</title>
      <link>/music/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 14:15:35 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/music/</guid>
      <description>Aditi Song
Date: 11 Sept 2021
   Cool Punk - 2021!
Date: 13 Mar 2021
   வான்! - Vaan!
Date: 28 Sept 2020
   வானவிலே! - Vaanavilae!
Date: 3 May 2020
   The Corona Anthem!
Date: 19 Apr 2020
   Silent Smile
Date: 28 Jan 2020
   Only Love
Date: 20 Jan 2020
   Vivid Dreams</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A 24 year old&#39;s struggle to learn Music</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-04-22-a-24yr-olds-struggle-to-learn-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-04-22-a-24yr-olds-struggle-to-learn-music/</guid>
      <description>Firstly listen to the below wonderful piece composed by Ludovico Einaudi
  Did you notice the talent? The involvement? The fingers moving effortlessly with absolute passion for the tune? The background orchestra supporting like pillars of a beautiful monument? The violins and cellos. This is a thing of a beauty. Now this is one beautiful example of a sincere and a passionate work. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it?
I am a 24 year old aspiring Keyboard student.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop The Goddamn Car !</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-06-17-stop-the-goddamn-car/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 05:35:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-06-17-stop-the-goddamn-car/</guid>
      <description>Ever felt really bad after a stupid argument? over a stupid topic? with your close ones? Ever felt so exhausted after such bad moments and started to regret things? I also have encountered such moments. I recently got an important advice from my dad which was more like a solution to such kind of problems. So I thought I could share it with the world.
I admired these words so much and tried to understand it better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inspiration from within !</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-04-20-inspiration-from-within/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 06:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-04-20-inspiration-from-within/</guid>
      <description>In my opinion, clearly no person other than Steve Jobs will be remembered by the world for what he did to technology and design. No other batsman other than Sachin Tendulkar is rightly portrayed to be the &amp;lsquo;God of Cricket&amp;rsquo; for what he did to the game and for Indian cricket. No one other than Narayana Murthy will be appreciated in India as much for being a role model and perfect entrepreneur in the Indian IT industry.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
